<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Immigration | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/immigration/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/immigration/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Immigration</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Immigration</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/immigration/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Syrian immigration</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-alrahil/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-alrahil/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;article&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-11-01-alrahil/article_hu8b18c731028e781abd295ea366f2897b_250911_b2e0a4c10e71933f0c0915c51d500198.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-11-01-alrahil/article_hu8b18c731028e781abd295ea366f2897b_250911_924434b7f96269287b24a049f0f14454.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-11-01-alrahil/article_hu8b18c731028e781abd295ea366f2897b_250911_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-alrahil/article_hu8b18c731028e781abd295ea366f2897b_250911_b2e0a4c10e71933f0c0915c51d500198.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;532&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Within the issue of October 8, 1907 under the Local and General Section, an interesting deviation from the normalities of that column appeared. Within this small paragraph it is discussed that a heavier influx of Syrians, which could describe both people from what is known as modern day Syria or from the Levant as a while, along with Chinese migrants to Jamaica. This “oriental” influx seemingly pushed the Government of Jamaica to prevent their entrance into the country, as it would pose a threat to local traders in the region. From this the City Council of Kingston pushed to amend the pauper alien immigration law to hinder the landing of “undesirable foreigners” in what was portrayed as an act of economic self preservation for other natives. The mention of this phenomenon mirrors the overarching trends found within this period, as Levantine/Syrian migration abroad for work had started becoming a more integral facet of the Middle Eastern existence and economy. This also coincided with other Eastern communities, especially Japanese and Chinese, doing the same, hence the mention of the Chinese immigrant influx as well within this short text. This started creating a new world social schema, and the racially targeted legislation that is seen being discussed had and would start popping up in different countries within the Western Hemisphere. This curiosity offers a small window in the overarching migrational patterns that characterized that time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;label&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-11-01-alrahil/featured_hucb0c15f804a8c45abf60e8367391067e_9055_23ae6fc4c1888eeac78361083e0c9e99.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-11-01-alrahil/featured_hucb0c15f804a8c45abf60e8367391067e_9055_54e3ae6e9f2e917e1d4d26584470ff9c.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-11-01-alrahil/featured_hucb0c15f804a8c45abf60e8367391067e_9055_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-alrahil/featured_hucb0c15f804a8c45abf60e8367391067e_9055_23ae6fc4c1888eeac78361083e0c9e99.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;248&#34;
               height=&#34;203&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sources&#34;&gt;Sources&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fahrenthold, Stacy D. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1093/acrefore/9780199329175.013.598.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;“Arab Labor Migration in the Americas, 1880–1930.”&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Oxford Research Encyclopedia of American History&lt;/em&gt; (2019).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicholls, David. &lt;a href=&#34;https://doi.org/10.1007/978-1-349-17786-8_9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;No Hawkers and Pedlars: Arabs of the Antilles&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;, in &lt;em&gt;Haiti in Caribbean Context&lt;/em&gt;, St Antony’s Series (Palgrave Macmillan, 1985).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nicholls, David. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.proquest.com/scholarly-journals/syrians-jamaica/docview/1292739482/se-2.&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;The &amp;ldquo;Syrians&amp;rdquo; of Jamaica.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;em&gt;Jamaican Historical Review&lt;/em&gt;, vol. 15, 1986, pp. 50.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The More Things Change</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-arenas/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-arenas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-more-things-change&#34;&gt;The More Things Change&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;the-more-they-stay-the-same&#34;&gt;The more they stay the same&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There is nothing new about racism or xenophobia, and it should be unsurprising, even expected, to find examples of orientalism in an &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/British-Imperialism/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;imperial newspaper&lt;/a&gt; aimed at colonial agents. What is surprising, and as an immigrant, more than a little upsetting, was reading a quoted article from &amp;ldquo;Home Counties Magasine&amp;rdquo; bemoaning the supposed death of the neighborhood of Whitechapel in East-end. The language used is frightfully familiar. &amp;ldquo;Extreme poverty is perhaps the most striking characteristic of this community&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; The unnamed writer goes on to describe just how &amp;ldquo;the typical alien in his English career&amp;rdquo; establishes himself. He finds a cheap room where he sleeps with his entire family and where he &amp;ldquo;plies his trade.&amp;rdquo; Expanding his business he recruits fellow immigrants, and they &amp;ldquo;dexterously avoid the eye of the law.&amp;rdquo; Ultimately, this faceless alien creates and propagates a nasty system of poverty, crime, and misery.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This viciously dehumanizing view of immigrants stands in bewildering contrast to other articles the Egyptian Gazette publishes observing native Egyptians daily. There is almost a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/abduh/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;respect&lt;/a&gt; given to some members of the Muslim community and the next day there is an article welcoming the construction of a Mosque in London!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Mosque&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/18-blog-arenas/1905-07-19-BlogImgMosque_hu251a2727dd4e358877a9d52c8360db49_472971_1dfaa19f77dbdafa52b549e1bfa59eab.webp 400w,
               /post/18-blog-arenas/1905-07-19-BlogImgMosque_hu251a2727dd4e358877a9d52c8360db49_472971_d23a037e3ec3fc893d5a0ba397929285.webp 760w,
               /post/18-blog-arenas/1905-07-19-BlogImgMosque_hu251a2727dd4e358877a9d52c8360db49_472971_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-arenas/1905-07-19-BlogImgMosque_hu251a2727dd4e358877a9d52c8360db49_472971_1dfaa19f77dbdafa52b549e1bfa59eab.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;263&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It seems that Great Britain had a &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/24427043?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=edwardian&amp;amp;searchText=racism&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3Facc%3Don%26amp%3Bwc%3Don%26amp%3BQuery%3Dedwardian%2Bracism%26amp%3Bfc%3Doff%26amp%3Bgroup%3Dnone&amp;amp;refreqid=search%3A755db30b4d0fb767b2f49b3c6b757e39&amp;amp;seq=1#page_scan_tab_contents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;history&lt;/a&gt; of Anti-Semitism in this era that also saw the Dreyfus affair and the proliferation of biological racism that further dehumanized non-white groups. Oscar Slater, for example, was a British Jew living in Glasgow in 1908, and like Dreyfus was wrongfully convicted of a crime he did not commit, in this case the murder of a white British woman. I can only hazard a guess as to why such a heinously racist view of Jewish immigrants in Whitechapel can coexist with the apparent celebration of Muslim culture. The closest I can understand is the idea of &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.jstor.org/stable/25691223?Search=yes&amp;amp;resultItemClick=true&amp;amp;searchText=edwardian&amp;amp;searchText=racism&amp;amp;searchUri=%2Faction%2FdoBasicSearch%3Facc%3Don%26amp%3Bwc%3Don%26amp%3BQuery%3Dedwardian%2Bracism%26amp%3Bfc%3Doff%26amp%3Bgroup%3Dnone&amp;amp;refreqid=search%3A755db30b4d0fb767b2f49b3c6b757e39&amp;amp;seq=5#page_scan_tab_contents&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;defensive imperialism&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; Historian Eric Adler in an article in the &lt;em&gt;International Journal of the Classical Tradition&lt;/em&gt; posits that Late-Victorian/Edwardian imperialists sought to define the British empire in terms with which they could compare it to the Roman empire. Unlike the Romans, Adler posits that a popular refrain of British imperialism was that they effectively sought to &amp;ldquo;protect&amp;rdquo; themselves by expanding. As subjects of British rule, Muslim Egyptians are thus &amp;ldquo;ok&amp;rdquo; so long as they stay in their separate sphere, since they are not &amp;ldquo;intruding&amp;rdquo; into British space, unlike the Eastern European Jews that are immigrating to Whitechapel. The whole point of empire, other than enrichment, is to protect the colonial nation from the subjects of &lt;em&gt;other&lt;/em&gt; empires when they &amp;ldquo;invade&amp;rdquo; (I cannot stress the quotation marks there enough) home. The new Eastern European Jewish community therefore turns the idea of Empire on its head.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
