<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Wyatt Bush | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/wyattbush/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/wyattbush/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Wyatt Bush</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/wyattbush/avatar_hu5da1a3994fe0a0b775b79de918c189e0_74056_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Wyatt Bush</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/wyattbush/</link></image><item><title>Pre-War Anglo-German Relations</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-bush/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-bush/</guid><description>&lt;p>This article, of the June 23rd 1906 edition of the Egyptian Gazette shows an occasion in which members of the English and German governments met and even formed a social group, the Anglo-German Friendship committee. The committee was founded in 1905, by British and German diplomats, and found support even in America, mostly from the German-American population. The proceedings and the speakers invited to present all alluded to a strong, amicable alliance between two of the strongest powers in the world, both in imperial territory, military might, and economic prowess. This is particularly amusing because of the bitter irony that these two nations will be at each others throats engaged in the trenches of the first world war in under a decade. It will be several decades more before anything resembling friendship between Britain and Germany will exist again. I wonder as to the effectiveness of this organization, and if the German diplomats had any genuine desire to make friendship, as this appeared to be a endeavor mostly pushed, funded, and spearheaded by the british diplomats and politicians. In turn I wonder if the English did this as a front in the expectation of war, to appear as the pacifists that tried to stop it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>