<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Julia Cavaliere | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/juliacavaliere/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/juliacavaliere/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Julia Cavaliere</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/juliacavaliere/avatar_hu5da1a3994fe0a0b775b79de918c189e0_74056_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Julia Cavaliere</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/juliacavaliere/</link></image><item><title>Narrowing Results</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/</guid><description>&lt;p>An issue faced by all the members of our group, when doing individual analysis, was getting narrower results for our related research questions, while making sure our queries still had enough relevant results. In order to tackle this issue, we devised a methodology to test the relevance of the queries used in our individual analysis. For future research projects, I have outlined the basic process below:&lt;/p>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Gather relevant keywords to your research question. Try to get a list of at least 5 or so words that are concise enough to yield relevant results, but not too little.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run count queries for those words and keep track of how many results you get for each. If you can, look at some of the results, and see if there are any “stock words” that you can use to exclude in subsequent queries.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Run more queries with narrower parameters and keep track of how many results are yielded. Make sure to exclude stock words.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Divide the number of narrow queries by the more generalized result and calculate the percentage.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>With these percentages, you can now tell how relevant your specifications are, in regard to your larger research question. If some queries are only 2% of the larger data pool, that would likely be not as significant compared to a query of 38%. Interpreting this data and incorporating it into your individual analysis can be done however you choose.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;p>The overall purpose of this method is to provide a quick way to clarify and measure the relevancy of potential queries you may have for your project. Seeing how correlated your queries are to larger ideas and phrases that are present in the Egyptian gazette can help gather a more concise data pool to draw on for your analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="what-we-were-trying-to-accomplish-as-a-group-and-as-an-individual">What we were trying to accomplish (as a group and as an individual)&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>The purpose of this was to determine how effective a certain query was at returning results relevant to what was being researched. A lot of our initial queries returned hundreds of results, but only a certain percentage of those results contained any relevant information. Furthermore, there was often a pattern in the initial query’s results that allowed for the exclusion or inclusion of certain words or terms to help narrow things down. Because of this, we used the method of refining our initial queries and calculated a percentage to determine the relevance of the results produced.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>One example of this was a query used to find associations with the word “pain” in the paper. The initial query returned 585 results with only 244 of those results being relevant. The other 341 results contained information irrelevant to what was being sought after. This means that the initial query was about 41.7% successful at returning relevant results. Obviously, there is room for improvement. Interestingly, about 31.6% of the results from the initial query contained the word “painting”. Clearly, these results were not relevant to what was being sought after, so by running the query again but excluding the word “painting” this time, the results proved to be far more relevant. This time, 61% of the results contained relevant information. This is about a 20% difference between the two queries, meaning that, now, most of the results contain relevant information.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="pain" srcset="
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_49a943afeb7a725be66b2270979eff39.webp 400w,
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_fbe85ab895843ff3af6ee5c2d5b171e6.webp 760w,
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_49a943afeb7a725be66b2270979eff39.webp"
width="760"
height="454"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another example was finding specific words associated with “ivory”. While Ivory itself gave 233 results, divs containing “packages ivory” came to 60 results, or roughly a quarter of all instances of Ivory. Searching for divs that contained both the words “ivory” and “tusk” gave only 12 results (5% of all results) , which meant that there was far less results to use in my analysis. By having these numbers available, I knew how I wanted to guide my research, and was able to use the 12 results for a more in-depth analysis, while packages of ivory could give raw data in discussing the context in which animals were viewed in the Egyptian gazette.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="ivory" srcset="
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_822d4619d36d6ed2d454e48d77d8b6f7.webp 400w,
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_08c24edd81ab84f6aae7d2ebb4dfc062.webp 760w,
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_822d4619d36d6ed2d454e48d77d8b6f7.webp"
width="760"
height="452"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This example shows queries to find sections that included words associated with the Assouan Dam. This was a bit more complex as the keyword is two different words. This required the query to add sections that would include “Assouan Dam” or (“Assouan” and “Dam”) together. There were 96 initial results for “Assouan Dam” and 263 counts of “Assouan” and “Dam” not including “Assouan Dam”. This was a total of 359 results, with 114 being relevant. This shows that 32.6% of results were relevant. There were a lot of irrelevant results caused by the word “Dam”. For instance, this brought up information related to “Damascus” or “Rotterdam”. The query search was updated to look for “Assouan” and “ Dam “. This included a space before and after “dam” so that it would search for whole words only. This created a total of 117 results, meaning only 3 results were not relevant. This query resulted in a 97.4% relevant return.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="tableau" srcset="
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_70374c2e405a58d0a49ef044ed01c898.webp 400w,
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_5d048ea2bcb9a8d0beec2288cc7ac332.webp 760w,
/post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_70374c2e405a58d0a49ef044ed01c898.webp"
width="760"
height="738"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This graph compiled all our relevancy trends into one chart, where ivory was in red, pain in teal, assouan dam in blue and Ryan’s in orange. Blue and teal each had similar trends, where the initial query was much larger than the later queries, but held less relevance. In the “pain” query case, that word gave more hits because it was in words like “painting”, which were not relevant to the analysis project. Future queries narrowed down the results, but made them more relevant to the subject being studied. Ryan’s analysis (orange) began with very few results and relevancy, and as the search went on, more accurate and functioning queries were made, which yielded more relevant results. The assoaun dam query, similar to “pain” dealt with multiple spellings and context for the dam. As the queries narrowed down, proper spelling, along with proper context increased, though total number of hits decreased. For the ivory query, there were multiple instances of the word mentioned, which had a lot of relevancy to the main topic. As the queries narrowed, they were designed to see if two subjects were at all related in relevancy, to test the hypothesis of the analysis. As the results narrowed, so to did the relevacny, which was valuable to the data gathered regarding the ivory trade.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="how-future-students-can-use-it">How future students can use it&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our method of breaking down larger queries into more concise, filtered results was intended to help guide early research questions, and determine what stock words could be included (or excluded) from narrower queries. For future students of this class, using a simple graph to evaluate their early queries can help them visualize how feasible their potential research topic is. Additionally, from a learning perspective, running a multitude of queries allows for students to familiarize themselves with the markup language, and provides an opportunity to tinker around and see what works and what doesn’t, while still yielding useful data in their project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This process is designed to be easy to use, quick to analyze, and simple to explain to others, as all you need to do is find a main word to search for, and produce as many smaller queries that you would like that contain that word. It is easy enough to divide the two results and make a bar graph to see how strongly related your queries are. If a future student were to query a word, like “army” and get back thousands of results, they could run finer searches that would exclude words, include the word “british”, or only find results on the third page, and see how much that skims down their data pool. If the pool is too shallow, it may not be the best to research. But if the data pool contains enough substantial evidence, while still being reasonable to look through, then that would pose a much more compelling research topic. This methodology we’ve designed is meant to help sort out and organize this process.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All in all, we felt like this methodology was effective in the very early stages of posing your analysis question. Filtering out false positives (like with the word “painting”) can be done before more refined queries are made, and a general sense of what data you are working with can be seen early on. Otherwise, this method felt lackluster for the more in-depth steps of our research projects because all it can provide is a preliminary visualization of where your data will lead you. However, this process does help provide a simple foundation and direction for the task at hand and the method used was successful at doing just that. For future classes, this would be most effective as a suggestion made towards students running a large query that contains too many results to narrow down their findings, or to help those with very little results broaden their scope.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Medicine and Ailments in The Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/</guid><description>&lt;p>For my analysis project, I decided to investigate the various medications advertised in the paper. The reason why I chose this was because of the crazy claims these advertisements made. Medication and remedies for certain illnesses and pains have existed for a very long time. However, regulations to produce these medications didn’t come along until way later. The earliest of these regulations started with voluntary drug approval in 1905, but it wasn’t until 1938 when regulations for drug safety were put in place (FDA, 2006). Because of this, a lot of these pharmaceutical companies could get away with making medications out of questionable ingredients and claiming that they cure a whole list of symptoms (Library of Congress). Most of these medications were manufactured in the U.S., as the country was one of the leaders in the pharmaceutical industry at the time (Hamilton, 1951). These medications were then exported to other parts of the world, including Alexandria, Egypt where advertisements for these medications appeared in the local newspaper. My goal with this project was to look at what health issues and medications were brought up the most in the newspaper, The Egyptian Gazette, with the purpose of finding correlations between the two and to paint a picture of what health and pharmacy were like in Alexandria in the early 1900s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>To accomplish this, I started by coming up with a list of medications advertised in the paper. This proved to be slightly difficult since all the advertisements are different and none of them are labeled the same. Instead, I tried to find a specific word that all the medication advertisements had in common. This word wound up being the word “druggist” since all the medication advertisements contained a line and distribution containing this word. I was then able to use the query &lt;code>//div//div[matches(., ‘druggist’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code> to find all the divs containing this word and, therefore, all the medications advertised. From there, I was able to comprise a list of 11 medications. The shortcoming of using this query, however, is that I probably missed any medications that had advertisements that did not contain this word. From there, I took each medication and used the query &lt;code>count(//div//div[matches(., “medication name”, ‘i’)])&lt;/code> to find the number of times each of these 10 medications were advertised in the paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After finding all the medications, I wanted to find out what ailments were mentioned the most in the paper. This was accomplished by looking at certain keywords associated with the word “pain”. The query used was &lt;code>\w+ \w+ pain\w* \w+ \w+&lt;/code> with the word “paint” being excluded in order to limit the number of false positives in my results. After this, the results were counted to see what ailments were associated the most with the word “pain”. The results of this query and the previous one were then analyzed and made into visualizations using Tableau.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Medications" srcset="
/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/medications_hu211a22abb13e95b5a966548850edfb5d_121971_b5e64760e03988ddf56e86ac1750c7ee.webp 400w,
/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/medications_hu211a22abb13e95b5a966548850edfb5d_121971_d86d74de19f2206c94cde4efbbe4e698.webp 760w,
/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/medications_hu211a22abb13e95b5a966548850edfb5d_121971_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/medications_hu211a22abb13e95b5a966548850edfb5d_121971_b5e64760e03988ddf56e86ac1750c7ee.webp"
width="760"
height="459"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This first visualization shows the results of the medication advertisements in the paper. Peruna by far had the most advertisements with 372, followed closely by Dr. William’s pink pills with 302. All other medications had less than half as many advertisements in the paper with some only having a handful.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Associations with the word &amp;amp;ldquo;Pain&amp;amp;rdquo;" srcset="
/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/associations_hu0db7bea89d31f52705fcc2e5f5d1c98d_85703_0c4f7ed0bc0fa9dc8f9652cd066e5bd3.webp 400w,
/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/associations_hu0db7bea89d31f52705fcc2e5f5d1c98d_85703_a373d735cfdf3536e98dae33bd329914.webp 760w,
/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/associations_hu0db7bea89d31f52705fcc2e5f5d1c98d_85703_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-cavaliere/associations_hu0db7bea89d31f52705fcc2e5f5d1c98d_85703_0c4f7ed0bc0fa9dc8f9652cd066e5bd3.webp"
width="760"
height="452"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next visualization shows the results of the ailments associated with “pain”. Back pain and rheumatism appeared the most frequently with 87 and 68 hits respectively. Chest pain and headaches have about half as many hits as rheumatism with 29 and 23. All other ailments produced less than 20 hits.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After doing some further research on each of the medications, some correlations can be made from these two sets of results. Back pain and rheumatism were two of the biggest complaints for ailments mentioned in the paper. Interestingly, the second most advertised medication, Dr. William’s pink pills, claims to be a treatment for rheumatism while the fourth most advertised medication, Doan’s backache and kidney pills, claims to be a treatment for backaches. So, it is clear that joint and back problems were common back in the early 1900s and medications for them were in high demand, hence the large number of advertisements. However, this pattern does not hold true for every medication. On the other hand, Peruna was by far the most advertised medication and is said to treat catarrh, but catarrh was only associated with pain a total of 4 times in the paper. This is a limitation of the query used. Catarrh is an illness caused by the buildup of mucus in the nose and throat, and while there are a few instances of illnesses being associated with “pain”, illnesses and diseases tend to not be described as painful (NHS, 2022). Therefore, very little of the results are made up of illnesses. A similar problem occurs with the third most advertised medication, Sanitas. Sanitas is a disinfectant used against bacterial infections. Bacterial infections were not associated at all with “pain”. This may be because bacterial infections weren’t considered to be painful, but other factors could’ve influenced this as well. For instance, bacterial and parasitic infections weren’t as common among the upper-class citizens who read this paper as they were for the working class, which is probably why these infections weren’t necessarily mentioned (Derr, 2019). This is also probably why there weren’t many medications advertised in the paper that treated these kinds of infections, as parasitic and bacterial infections were contracted mostly by the people working in the riverbanks and cotton fields (Derr, 2019). Overall, most of the other medications tend to follow the initial trend. Pastilles Valda, a remedy for chest pain, is the sixth most advertised medication while chest pain is the third most mentioned ailment. Doan’s dinner pills and Angier’s Emulsion are both stomach medications ranking at eighth and ninth for most advertised while stomach pain is the fifth most mentioned ailment. Despite the limitations, there is a trend of supply and demand that can be seen. For future studies, it may be beneficial to broaden the scope of the query used for ailments to include illnesses, diseases, and infections, which would help get an even more accurate idea of what health and pharmacy looked like in Alexandria in that time period.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="literature-cited">Literature Cited&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>Food and Drug Administration. (2006). A History of the FDA and Drug Regulation in the United States. FDA. Microsoft Word - 7B5F2254.doc (fda.gov)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Hamilton, B. (1951). The Medical Professions in the Eighteenth Century. The Economic History Review, 4(2), 141–169. &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.2307/2599120" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://doi.org/10.2307/2599120&lt;/a>&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Jennifer L. Derr, &amp;ldquo;Cruel Summer,&amp;rdquo; from &lt;em>The Lived Nile: Environment, Disease, and Material Colonial Economy in Egypt&lt;/em>. Stanford, California: Stanford University Press, 2019, 99-126.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Library of Congress. Catarrh Remedy and Peruna Scandal: Tpoics in the Chronicling America. Library of Congress. Introduction - Catarrh Remedy and Peruna Scandal: Topics in Chronicling America - Research Guides at Library of Congress (loc.gov)&lt;/li>
&lt;li>NHS. (2022). Catarrh. NHS. Catarrh - NHS (&lt;a href="https://www.nhs.uk" target="_blank" rel="noopener">www.nhs.uk&lt;/a>)&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol></description></item></channel></rss>