<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>France | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/france/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/france/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>France</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>France</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/france/</link></image><item><title>6,000 Birds Found Dead</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-14-fitzpatrick-post-birds/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-14-fitzpatrick-post-birds/</guid><description>&lt;p>I came across a morbidly funny article when reading through my week of the Egyptian Gazette. The title, &amp;ldquo;FATE OF 6,000 BIRDS&amp;rdquo; and to summarize the article briefly, after two nights of thick fog, nearly 6,000 birds were found dead under a lighthouse. They were attracted to the light in the fog and flew right against it. (The full article can be found in Page 4 of the &lt;a href="https://cdn.rawgit.com/dig-eg-gaz/content/master/1905-12-18.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Monday, December 18, 1905&lt;/a> issue of the Egyptian Gazette.) Not much else is mentioned in the article, it is a rather brief memorial. This struck me as being a unique article so I decided to share it. I did a quick search on the location of the lighthouse, &amp;ldquo;Cape Grisnez&amp;rdquo; and turns out this story takes place in France! Cape Grisnez is in northern France between Wissant and Audresselles. The cape held place to a naval battle during the Napoleonic Wars in 1805, and also would play a historical role in World War II. The lighthouse was built in 1837, originally standing 46 feet tall. In 1861, the lighthouse was raised to 79 feet tall.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading articles from the past makes the research more interesting, you read it from the perspective of the time frame it was written, but when investigating further you get a full picture that spans past the newspaper and through to present day. It just struck me funny how such a odd story could make international news, though granted the Egyptian
Gazette was sold to an audience of mainly Europeans.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;a href="http://www.lighthousedigest.com/digest/database/uniquelighthouse.cfm?value=5327" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Lighthouse Digest, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="http://www.francethisway.com/places/cap-gris-blanc-nez.php" target="_blank" rel="noopener">France This Way, Cape Gris Nez&lt;/a>
&lt;a href="https://www.unc.edu/~rowlett/lighthouse/fran.htm" target="_blank" rel="noopener">University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Lighthouses of France, North Coast&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Fashoda Incident</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/</guid><description>&lt;p>This small newspaper section addresses the infamous &lt;a href="https://www.britannica.com/event/Fashoda-Incident" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Fashoda Incident&lt;/a> that occurred between Britain and France during a period of intense colonialism in Africa. It shares that the ex-Prime Minister of France, &lt;a href="https://www.britannica.com/biography/Charles-Louis-de-Saulces-de-Freycinet" target="_blank" rel="noopener">M. de Freycinet&lt;/a>, is writing a book that promotes peace and cooperation between France and Britain.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The case he presents in &lt;a href="https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=uc1.$b749498;view=2up;seq=460" target="_blank" rel="noopener">his book&lt;/a> says that England was in the right during the Fashoda Incident but could have easily handled the situation better than they did. He also refutes the claims of the French courts, who said that the French response was a mistake. Put simply, he is about to publish a work that will try to put to rest misconceptions about the event that have been circulating through the public in an attempt to resolve any bad feelings.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is amazing to see this event described in an everyday context and even more fascinating that an ex-Prime Minister of France would declare England to be in the right, despite the competitive nature of colonial affairs. This entry is not only informational, but it also acts as an advertisement of sorts, presenting the name, author and content of a soon to be released book to the public eye. The information and arguments shared through the book may have strengthened Franco-British relations and helped lead to where the two powers stood during World War I.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="fashoda1" srcset="
/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/fashoda1_hu8cef3085e94cde96f041474d60497a07_17416_601bd3820c964f61d219c36ba779bb54.webp 400w,
/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/fashoda1_hu8cef3085e94cde96f041474d60497a07_17416_0d8dea22c4435d70ed58e751868eb06b.webp 760w,
/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/fashoda1_hu8cef3085e94cde96f041474d60497a07_17416_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-10-fashoda-incident/fashoda1_hu8cef3085e94cde96f041474d60497a07_17416_601bd3820c964f61d219c36ba779bb54.webp"
width="250"
height="300"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>