<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Alexander Amorello | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/alexanderamorello/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/alexanderamorello/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Alexander Amorello</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/alexanderamorello/avatar_hu5da1a3994fe0a0b775b79de918c189e0_74056_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Alexander Amorello</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/alexanderamorello/</link></image><item><title>A Reflection on the Tech</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-into-the-rabbit-hole-technical/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-into-the-rabbit-hole-technical/</guid><description>&lt;p>I feel like this second blog post is going to saturated with negatives, so I&amp;rsquo;ll try to keep mine a little brighter by starting with the fact that this initially pain-staking process has really grown on me. At first it was a total chore, slowly trouble shooting every single issue that I had with the multiple programs I had no familiarity with (Oxygen, ABBYY Finereader, and Github), wishing that my advisor would&amp;rsquo;ve warned better beforehand of such things and hoping that I would have a free weekend again.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But after about 3 solid weeks of working, something clicked. I started enjoying this previously arduous work. The trouble-shooting became enjoyable, as every issue came to me as an interesting puzzle rather than a pace-breaking wall. Also, the whole philosophy behind this encoding became much clearer to me, and in a way, inspired me to take special care when it came to encoding.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some things on the tech side that I believe led me to enjoying this process more were:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Having a larger monitor to work on: I like having all the information I need to encode in view all at once, it helps me keep things in order and it just keeps things more accurate. Having a monitor that is larger than a standard 13-15-17 in laptop screen really helped me. I was able to pull up boilerplates, have oxygen open, and have a reference scanned image open all in sizes that I could view easily. This expedited the process greatly&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Using a mouse: After trying to encode and OCR on my Surface and comparing it to my work on my desktop, I noticed a night and day difference in quality of pages and general frustration. The mouse allows you to have more exact control of your cursor and gives a less clunky access to your keyboard whilst moving your cursor between multiple points quickly.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>&amp;hellip;and some other technical mishaps/advice&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Make sure you take the highest quality scans of your microfilm as possible: Because I was foolish and decided to separate my scanning sessions into different days, I ended up getting two different qualities of scans. This made OCR&amp;rsquo;ing extremely frustrating as it made some pages correctable in about 20 minutes and other pages taking over an hour and a half. In short, SCAN HIGHEST DPI POSSIBLE AND MAKE SURE THE SCANNER GLASS DOES NOT HAVE EXCESSIVE SMUDGING.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>Always press Ctrl+S or &amp;ldquo;Save&amp;rdquo; after every page you finish in your issues: It&amp;rsquo;s been about 3 times that I&amp;rsquo;ve been so caught up in encoding that I forget to save for a few pages. Inevitably my computer updates or Oxygen crashes, and all that work is lost, leading to one too many instances of my palm colliding with my forehead.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>The &lt;a href="http://www.tei-c.org/index.xml" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TEI webpage&lt;/a> should be considered the holy text of this class. It is referenced by Dr. Hanley, and simple guides are available on dig-eg-gaz. But if you need find anything specific, get spiritual and make a journey into the rabbit hole.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul></description></item><item><title>Higher Learning through the Newspaper</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/</link><pubDate>Sun, 11 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/</guid><description>&lt;p>Within every issue throughout my week I continually saw two advertisements that stood out to me, an advertisement for a school of Language and an advertisement for an &amp;ldquo;English School&amp;rdquo;. Seeing education opportunities from the early 1900s is fascinating to me as it is during the century that public education became a cornerstone in developed nations.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>First are the Berlitz Schools of Languages, typically found under the &amp;ldquo;Cheap Pre-paid advertisement&amp;rdquo; column on Page 5&amp;rsquo;s. It sounded familiar to me, and after doing a brief amount of searching, this is a education company/institution that has persisted since 1878 all the way until to the present day, hailing from the state of Rhode Island. In 1905 however, students in Egypt would only be able to attend the locations present in Alexandria and Cairo, unlike now, as the Berlitz Corporation offers full courses online.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The next advert regarding education that intrigued me was the &amp;ldquo;English School, Nicosia&amp;rdquo; advertisement. Offering a range of subjects, from Turkish to Mathematics, this school seemed a little more similar to institutions of the modern day. Also, this school seemed to have a sessions of Cricket and Football to be played with the instructors, which struck me as something related to more modern school systems. After a small amount of searching, it appears that this school persisted to the modern day just as the Berlitz program did. Besides being one of the more &lt;a href="https://www.englishschool.ac.cy/schools-history" title="Nicosia English School Official History Page" target="_blank" rel="noopener">notable institutions of higher learning&lt;/a> in the Middle East, it is also an modern example of social change. For over two decades following the &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Turkish_invasion_of_Cyprus" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Turkish invasion of Cyprus&lt;/a>, Turkish students were not admitted into the school, becoming a predominantly Greek Cypriot institution. However in 2003, the English School opened it&amp;rsquo;s admission to Turkish Cypriots and it&amp;rsquo;s general admission numbers have only grown exponentially since then.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="image name" srcset="
/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/Nicosia_school_hub9defe2f6c125d9ffab517fc5f4b4a9e_87364_3b495cb21557abf2ab1945ad6b575381.webp 400w,
/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/Nicosia_school_hub9defe2f6c125d9ffab517fc5f4b4a9e_87364_1da5b446e5e368c7f9c753c94b5d4679.webp 760w,
/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/Nicosia_school_hub9defe2f6c125d9ffab517fc5f4b4a9e_87364_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-11-curiosity_berlitz_nicosia/Nicosia_school_hub9defe2f6c125d9ffab517fc5f4b4a9e_87364_3b495cb21557abf2ab1945ad6b575381.webp"
width="530"
height="648"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Even though during this time secondary education wasn&amp;rsquo;t seen as something that the whole of society deserved, it is still worth looking into these smaller institutions because it gives people a clearer understanding of how a system of education grows as more people become involved in it, and the social changes that occur through a better educated populace.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Letters to the Editor in the 1905 Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-amorello/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-amorello/</guid><description>&lt;p>Through the existence of newspapers, expressing opinions has become more acceptable and has developed over time into dedicating entire sections of the newspaper to it. These opinions formally come from the editors of the paper in the forms of editorials and the readers of the paper in the form of Letters to the Editor. Within the Egyptian Gazette in 1905, there are a wide selection of the Letters to the editor that were published and I wanted to examine them as a whole to hopefully gain some insight on what the readers of the Egyptian Gazette are concerned about. Were the primarily British readers more interested in the financial content of the newspaper? Alternatively, did they want make a point known about the culture in Alexandria at the time? What follows is an examination of peoples that are not talked about in the historical mainstream, not men with fancy hats who rule over others, but a more common folk.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Before starting, it would be beneficial to go over the process that I used to collect the data I found regarding these letters. Before I started querying the issues, I wanted to skim through multiple weeks to see what sections of the newspaper were common and had something that stood out to me. I look through my week, spanning from September 18 to September 23, along with the weeks that were finished up by some classmates I knew in class. Initially, I took interest in the analysis of orchestra performances in Alexandria, seeing what composers were most popular in the city and what groups were being utilized most often (military bands, community orchestras, national orchestras, etc). Querying for this information was inconclusive, even after extensive manipulation of the queries. This led me to pick the letters to the editor. They had a more common appearance in the paper and had a more standard lay out in the issues throughout the year. After compiling the most recently updated issues of the paper into a project in Oxygen Text Editor, I started querying multiple terms in the boilerplate header for the letters. I looked for terms such as “editor”, “free discussion”, and “fair play”, as these terms appeared to be more common in letters to the editor header than any other article I had read. This resulted in far too many results to look through, a lot of which had nothing to do with what I wanted to find, much of it reporting on rival newspapers or correspondents. I decided to be more specific, targeting the header itself using the &lt;code>//div[@type=&amp;quot;item&amp;quot;][contains(., 'LETTERS TO THE EDITOR')]&lt;/code> query. Not yielding the results I had expected, I decided to make it even broader and look in every div regardless of type using &lt;code>//div[contains(., 'LETTERS TO THE EDITOR')]&lt;/code>. This worked fine, resulting in roughly 45 actual letters to the editor. Still expecting to see more I decided to look for more specifics in the boilerplate. I later found out that two boilerplates had been made for the heading of the letters to the editor. One the used “Letters” and another that specified a single letter “Letter to the Editor”. I queried that exactly headline using &lt;code>//div [contains(., 'LETTER TO THE EDITOR')]&lt;/code> and managed to find an additional 20 letters. With a total of 65 letters accounted for, I decided to move into the analysis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After looking through each of the letters published in the newspaper, some things became apparent very quickly. The vast majority of these the people writing to the Egyptian Gazette utilize this section as a way to discuss Local/National problems. They most often respond to a previous issue of the Gazette and start posing an opposite viewpoint to what the writer of the paper wrote. One repeating occurrence in this section is complaints about the “savages” in Egypt, which, in most of cases, is referring to the non-educated native Egyptian population of Alexandria. In one letter, a Mr. “A. Mermaid” is complaining about the indecency of Arab families and Low-class Europeans near his bathing box. He finishes his rant: “Egypt is no doubt improving for the Egyptians, but the Egyptians are not improving it. Among the many things that Lord Cromer is having taught to the Egyptians might it not be advisable to include decency!!!”.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Another thing that seemed to pop up within the letters to the editor was the concern that many readers had regarding the treatment of animals. For example, during the latter half of May and early June, multiple letters were published regarding Pigeon Shooting. A sporting club in England had banned pigeon shooting and many readers were writing in to try to convince the Alexandria Sports Club to ban the sport as well. All of the letters published were in favor of banning the act, calling it a game rather than a sport. One thing that stuck out to me regarding these responses was that no one had included their real name as the writer, always using a pseudonym (some being comedic, such as “Disgusted”, “Clay-Pigeon”, or “British Pigeon”).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Additionally, the people who wrote to the editor of the Egyptian Gazette had at least some concern about the public good. Occasionally the letters brought up the matter of public goods, such as new water pumps, public institutions of learning, and Anglo-Egyptian Hospitals but it could be reasonably assumed that these public goods were to benefit the British rather than the native Egyptians. Furthermore, many of the letters regarded experiences of luxury, such as trying to get the Egyptian Gazette to contain a full review of an Opera or the suggestion that train companies should provide free Tea to the riders of their trains.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>International News was a less common topic discussed by the letters published in the Egyptian Gazette, but was still brought up enough to be noticeable. One notable letter that was published regarded a Swedish national requesting that the editor add new information about what the newspaper called the “Scandinavian Quarrel”, stating that the Swedish Government would not accept the frontier fortresses established by Norway in the late 1890s.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, a small amount of the letters talked about financial occurrences, including a speculation of the change of prices at the Suez Canal and the long lasting effects of the Capitulations. The amount of financial discussion surprised me as the majority of the Egyptian Gazette contains financial information and advertisements, whereas the letters to the editors did not.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I borrowed part of the Schema from the TEI encoding process and used that to put the analysis into a visual format. I utilized the scope tags “Financial”, “International”, and “Local” but decided to change the Local scope into a “National” scope as many of the letters regarded many parts of Egypt rather than just simply Alexandria. After establishing these categories, I went through each of the letters that I found and sorted them into their tag. I chose these tags specifically because of their ties to the normal layout of the newspaper itself. The three main sections of the newspaper were Local/General, International, and Finance, so presumably, the readers of the paper had at least some interest in predominant topics or else the paper would not bother producing new articles every day.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Serial Question" srcset="
/post/16-analysis-amorello/amorello-analysis_hu136d6740d7d56c6bcdc735a96e75b3f9_31404_a85abf1a5652a12986ed8cfec60acf48.webp 400w,
/post/16-analysis-amorello/amorello-analysis_hu136d6740d7d56c6bcdc735a96e75b3f9_31404_f36e4f1a1d1a7f5c6258d23908e0b828.webp 760w,
/post/16-analysis-amorello/amorello-analysis_hu136d6740d7d56c6bcdc735a96e75b3f9_31404_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-amorello/amorello-analysis_hu136d6740d7d56c6bcdc735a96e75b3f9_31404_a85abf1a5652a12986ed8cfec60acf48.webp"
width="760"
height="568"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>From this categorization, I found that the vast majority of the published letters to the editor regarded things going on within Egypt itself, coming in with just about 74% of the total published letters. Letters regarding international topics were significantly less popular than national topics, comprising about 19% of the letters published. Surprisingly, the smallest category was Financial, only being mentioned in five letters, making up about 7% of the total letters published.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In conclusion, I found that the readers of the Egyptian Gazette preferred to discuss more cultural and local topics than either International or Financial topics, something that you would not have gleamed from just glancing at the average content of the Egyptian Gazette, a paper primarily produced for the consumption of businessmen of Alexandria. Additionally, the common man that reads and responds to this newspaper is not the average person present in Alexandria in 1905. The person that would read and possibly respond to the paper would most likely be a non-native of Egypt, a foreign businessman. Throughout the length of this course, the concept of Microhistory has become approachable. Microhistory tries to take smaller events and individuals and make a compelling observation with them, hoping to get away from the approach of using “great men” to define history. While I believe my approach in trying to find the more about the “smaller units” in Egypt using the letters is a step in the right direction, I can see how it is still hindered by its confined group of readers. The readers/writers of these letters may be a “smaller unit” than Lord Cromer, but these businessmen/educated men are still a minority in Egypt, and trying to make any overarching generalizations based on these newspaper readers would not be accurate for the society in Egypt, only the minority that actually were able to read the paper.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Finally, regarding the shortcomings of Digital methods in Microhistory, the amount of labor to get a searchable database is considerably large. It definitely requires combined effort for large works and a solid schema needs to be developed and cemented before the encoding begins, or else massive inconsistencies will arise when trying to query the data later. However, if these are all worked through, and a clean database is established, the power to query huge amounts of data to conduct research is incredibly effective. It opens up the possibility of more quantitative data to support historical research, previously something more common in the hard sciences. In the end, Digital Methods are the way to go, but the processes just needs to be established more clearly for each project that the methods are used in.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>