<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>MasonMacalka | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/masonmacalka/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/masonmacalka/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>MasonMacalka</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>MasonMacalka</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/masonmacalka/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Narrowing Results</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An issue faced by all the members of our group, when doing individual analysis, was getting narrower results for our related research questions, while making sure our queries still had enough relevant results. In order to tackle this issue, we devised a methodology to test the relevance of the queries used in our individual analysis. For future research projects, I have outlined the basic process below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gather relevant keywords to your research question. Try to get a list of at least 5 or so words that are concise enough to yield relevant results, but not too little.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run count queries for those words and keep track of how many results you get for each. If you can, look at some of the results, and see if there are any “stock words” that you can use to exclude in subsequent queries.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Run more queries with narrower parameters and keep track of how many results are yielded. Make sure to exclude stock words.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Divide the number of narrow queries by the more generalized result and calculate the percentage.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With these percentages, you can now tell how relevant your specifications are, in regard to your larger research question. If some queries are only 2% of the larger data pool, that would likely be not as significant compared to a query of 38%. Interpreting this data and incorporating it into your individual analysis can be done however you choose.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The overall purpose of this method is to provide a quick way to clarify and measure the relevancy of potential queries you may have for your project. Seeing how correlated your queries are to larger ideas and phrases that are present in the Egyptian gazette can help gather a more concise data pool to draw on for your analysis.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-we-were-trying-to-accomplish-as-a-group-and-as-an-individual&#34;&gt;What we were trying to accomplish (as a group and as an individual)&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The purpose of this was to determine how effective a certain query was at returning results relevant to what was being researched. A lot of our initial queries returned hundreds of results, but only a certain percentage of those results contained any relevant information. Furthermore, there was often a pattern in the initial query’s results that allowed for the exclusion or inclusion of certain words or terms to help narrow things down. Because of this, we used the method of refining our initial queries and calculated a percentage to determine the relevance of the results produced.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One example of this was a query used to find associations with the word “pain” in the paper. The initial query returned 585 results with only 244 of those results being relevant. The other 341 results contained information irrelevant to what was being sought after. This means that the initial query was about 41.7% successful at returning relevant results. Obviously, there is room for improvement. Interestingly, about 31.6% of the results from the initial query contained the word “painting”. Clearly, these results were not relevant to what was being sought after, so by running the query again but excluding the word “painting” this time, the results proved to be far more relevant. This time, 61% of the results contained relevant information. This is about a 20% difference between the two queries, meaning that, now, most of the results contain relevant information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;pain&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_49a943afeb7a725be66b2270979eff39.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_fbe85ab895843ff3af6ee5c2d5b171e6.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/pain_hu4bfd606913c2c5c62e23585c8c1aad0a_78771_49a943afeb7a725be66b2270979eff39.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;454&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another example was finding specific words associated with “ivory”. While Ivory itself gave 233 results, divs containing “packages ivory” came to 60 results, or roughly a quarter of all instances of Ivory. Searching for divs that contained both the words “ivory” and “tusk” gave only 12 results (5% of all results) , which meant that there was far less results to use in my analysis. By having these numbers available, I knew how I wanted to guide my research, and was able to use the 12 results for a more in-depth analysis, while packages of ivory could give raw data in discussing the context in which animals were viewed in the Egyptian gazette.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;ivory&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_822d4619d36d6ed2d454e48d77d8b6f7.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_08c24edd81ab84f6aae7d2ebb4dfc062.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/ivory_hud1a5d6f583dcd8b4b2a8f946f4a10329_85647_822d4619d36d6ed2d454e48d77d8b6f7.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;452&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example shows queries to find sections that included words associated with the Assouan Dam. This was a bit more complex as the keyword is two different words. This required the query to add sections that would include “Assouan Dam” or (“Assouan” and “Dam”) together. There were 96 initial results for “Assouan Dam” and 263 counts of “Assouan” and “Dam” not including “Assouan Dam”. This was a total of 359 results, with 114 being relevant. This shows that 32.6% of results were relevant. There were a lot of irrelevant results caused by the word “Dam”. For instance, this brought up information related to “Damascus” or “Rotterdam”. The query search was updated to look for “Assouan” and 	           “ Dam “. This included a space before and after “dam” so that it would search for whole words only. This created a total of 117 results, meaning only 3 results were not relevant. This query resulted in a 97.4% relevant return.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;tableau&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_70374c2e405a58d0a49ef044ed01c898.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_5d048ea2bcb9a8d0beec2288cc7ac332.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-results-group/tableau_hubd31c8ba1203ebf52c01a78127945c9a_88352_70374c2e405a58d0a49ef044ed01c898.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;738&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This graph compiled all our relevancy trends into one chart, where ivory was in red, pain in teal, assouan dam in blue and Ryan’s in orange. Blue and teal each had similar trends, where the initial query was much larger than the later queries, but held less relevance. In the “pain” query case, that word gave more hits because it was in words like “painting”, which were not relevant to the analysis project. Future queries narrowed down the results, but made them more relevant to the subject being studied. Ryan’s analysis (orange) began with very few results and relevancy, and as the search went on, more accurate and functioning queries were made, which yielded more relevant results. The assoaun dam query, similar to “pain” dealt with multiple spellings and context for the dam. As the queries narrowed down, proper spelling, along with proper context increased, though total number of hits decreased. For the ivory query, there were multiple instances of the word mentioned, which had a lot of relevancy to the main topic. As the queries narrowed, they were designed to see if two subjects were at all related in relevancy, to test the hypothesis of the analysis. As the results narrowed, so to did the relevacny, which was valuable to the data gathered regarding the ivory trade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-future-students-can-use-it&#34;&gt;How future students can use it&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our method of breaking down larger queries into more concise, filtered results was intended to help guide early research questions, and determine what stock words could be included (or excluded) from narrower queries. For future students of this class, using a simple graph to evaluate their early queries can help them visualize how feasible their potential research topic is. Additionally, from a learning perspective, running a multitude of queries allows for students to familiarize themselves with the markup language, and provides an opportunity to tinker around and see what works and what doesn’t, while still yielding useful data in their project.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This process is designed to be easy to use, quick to analyze, and simple to explain to others, as all you need to do is find a main word to search for, and produce as many smaller queries that you would like that contain that word. It is easy enough to divide the two results and make a bar graph to see how strongly related your queries are. If a future student were to query a word, like “army” and get back thousands of results, they could run finer searches that would exclude words, include the word “british”, or only find results on the third page, and see how much that skims down their data pool. If the pool is too shallow, it may not be the best to research. But if the data pool contains enough substantial evidence, while still being reasonable to look through, then that would pose a much more compelling research topic. This methodology we’ve designed is meant to help sort out and organize this process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All in all, we felt like this methodology was effective in the very early stages of posing your analysis question. Filtering out false positives (like with the word “painting”) can be done before more refined queries are made, and a general sense of what data you are working with can be seen early on. Otherwise, this method felt lackluster for the more in-depth steps of our research projects because all it can provide is a preliminary visualization of where your data will lead you. However, this process does help provide a simple foundation and direction for the task at hand and the method used was successful at doing just that. For future classes, this would be most effective as a suggestion made towards students running a large query that contains too many results to narrow down their findings, or to help those with very little results broaden their scope.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Assouan Dam</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-macalka/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-macalka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The topic I chose was the significance of the Assouan Dam in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. I chose this topic because I thought it would be interesting to research something that is not inside Cairo or Alexandria, which makes up a majority of the Gazette&amp;quot;s news. When looking for a topic, I found trouble trying to find something that was significant on a global scale or at least outside of Egypt and the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. I found the Assouan Dam when I saw almost an entire half-page dedicated to it, and after further research found a story that had continued throughout the four years of news that is available. Assouan was an area that was both rich in agriculture as well as tourism and historical importance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Located on the border of the Upper Nile and Lower Nile, a dam was built in 1902 to help the agricultural industry as well as to protect Philae, an island in the Nile with an ancient temple complex. The temples were built around 6th-7th Century BC and is Assouan&amp;quot;s biggest tourist attraction even to this day. Due to Philae being a small island that had little elevation, it was prone to flooding if there was no control on the water level. Cotton, grains, and lentils were major crops that would be exported to Cairo and presumably around the world. It required the Nile to be at a steady level so that the fields would not get flooded. In early 1905, articles in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; showed people complaining that the dam was not high enough and floods would eventually come and ruin Philae and the crops. However, the government did not care, and they did not raise the dam. In 1906, architects or scientists would show how the flooding is on track to breach the dam. In late 1906, letters to the editor included some stern messages to the government demanding for money to be allocated to the raising of the dam, still with no success. In July 1907, the dam flooded and ruined a lot of fields and flooded Philae, causing extensive damage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This was included in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; likely because Assouan was a major agricultural hub that would supply Alexandria and Cairo with crops. When I researched other reasons Assouan was included in the newspaper, the most common appearances were in the export and import sections, as well as stating when ferries or boats were departing from a port to go to Assouan. This was also included because the federal government was responsible for allocating funds to the construction and re-raising of the dam, not a local government. The &amp;ldquo;Letter to the Editors&amp;rdquo; section included several messages from people who were complaining or demanding these changes in Assouan, so that made it a big deal up in North Egypt where the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was published.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This analysis project looks at the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; to see what context the Assouan Dam is in throughout the newspaper. Originally using the &amp;ldquo;Find/Replace&amp;rdquo; tool inside Oxygen XML, I came across a lot of improper results for a lot of key words or phrases. Another issue I came across was word capitalization. I added a tag in my queries to make the word searches not case sensitive. Lastly, another tweak I made when querying was for the word &amp;ldquo;dam&amp;rdquo; adding spaces before and after (&lt;code&gt; dam &lt;/code&gt;) so that it would pick up whole words rather than parts of words such as &amp;ldquo;Damascus&amp;rdquo;. Instead of finding how many times each word was said as well, I decided to count instances based on the number of sections included each term. This created a constant for all words as well, just showing how relevant they were instead of how common a word was stated. One section could repeat &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo; ten times and be as relevant as a section whose header is &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo; and it not stated again in the paragraphs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The XML query format I used throughout this entire project was &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;page&amp;quot;]/div/p[matches(., &amp;quot;assouan&amp;quot;, &#39;i&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt; or if there was multiple words I needed to search for, &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;page&amp;quot;]/div/p[matches(., &#39;assouan&#39;, &#39;i&#39;) and matches(., &#39; dam &#39;, &#39;i&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prior to querying, I read about 20 sections that talked about the dam in order to see what was relevant to the topic. I found that a majority of sections about the dam talked or referred to one of three topics: agriculture, architecture, or the government. After initial querying, I found that some sections would not show up, so I had to group some keywords together into a section. Government was independent, agriculture included &amp;ldquo;irrigation&amp;rdquo;, while architecture included &amp;ldquo;temple&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Philae&amp;rdquo;. I wanted to visualize the instances of these sections in a way that was different than a bar graph.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bar graphs are efficient in showing one dimension, which is counting instances. However, I added another dimension to the data visualization by showing overlap ofinstances between two or three keywords as well. A lot of important keywords were related, which stems back to my research topic. In order to visualize my data, I used Adobe Photoshop to create a landscape of rectangles that would clearly show a size difference that was based on the number of instances. I could not use squares or the exact same ratio rectangles because the number of keywords I queried for would not fit visually. In order to adapt to this issue, I made the equation:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instances × 1000 = size of rectangle (in pixels)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Even though the instances was multiplied by 1000, this did not mean this was the height and width of the rectangle. 1000 was my starting point, however it was often reduced to cater to size restrictions. If I cut 1000 in half, I would multiply the number of instances by 2 so that the shape has the exact same number of pixels still. This effectively showed the number of instances of each term despite occasionally having different ratios. Most shapes had a width of 1000, 500, 333.3, 250, or 200, all of which were easily divisible of 1000. This meant the heights of shapes were commonly instances multiplied by 1, 2, 3, 4, or 5.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;results-and-data-visualization&#34;&gt;Results and Data Visualization:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The complete results are following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;overall&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/new_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_3829882_7bd61d4430678ad9b81a361b49c4991d.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/new_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_3829882_392a6a0bd6622d9496ed51de0afe731d.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/new_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_3829882_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-macalka/new_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_3829882_7bd61d4430678ad9b81a361b49c4991d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each shape represents the number of instances. A scale is in the bottom left corner for reference. Some of the major words feature their counts for viewers to understand. Any square where a &amp;ldquo;+&amp;rdquo; is present means both or all of these terms are present in a section. Because &amp;ldquo;Assouan&amp;rdquo; is the main keyword, despite it being the third largest, I gave it a textured design to help it stick out more. Shapes with a blue or similar background are related to government, yellow, gold, and orange is agriculture, greens are related to architecture, while pinks and purples are unrelated to any of those three major topics. Inside the &amp;ldquo;Assouan&amp;rdquo; shape is &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo;, where inside that is what other keywords are combined.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The main data that was collected is nearly impossible to read without zooming in. The following zoomed images show &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo; in relation to &amp;ldquo;Assouan&amp;rdquo;, as well as the &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo; topics alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;zoom1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom1_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_256885_c20ea17eb3327d7e13844c3ca9473e63.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom1_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_256885_3d14ba94a99110f1a4b13764f4535ff5.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom1_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_256885_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom1_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_256885_c20ea17eb3327d7e13844c3ca9473e63.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;243&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;zoom2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom2_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_38000_a429cdafa1d416c3fc26e69f253af17c.webp 400w,
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom2_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_38000_dad752254088cd2aff6d4a0344d74906.webp 760w,
               /post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom2_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_38000_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2023-analysis-macalka/zoom2_huebbfad1edfa8e198fe68a27ac6a615ca_38000_a429cdafa1d416c3fc26e69f253af17c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;343&#34;
               height=&#34;361&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section Agr. refers to (Assouan Dam + Agriculture + Irrigation)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section Arch. refers to (Assouan Dam + Architecture + Philae + Temple)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Section Other refers to sections that do not include any of the following terms&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo; was referenced 117 times in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in the available issues. 114 of these were related to the three main topics, with only 3 being unrelated to any of those. There were no instances of &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Architecture&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Agriculture&amp;rdquo; all in the same section. However, there were 3 instances of &amp;ldquo;Assouan Dam&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Government&amp;rdquo;, and &amp;ldquo;Agriculture&amp;rdquo; in the same section, hence the shape between the two. One of the sections that was in the &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo; category was an obituary to a deceased Assouan Dam construction worker. The other two both were broadly about water levels. I did not make this its own section because it was not including statistics and it just was not relevant in the general scope of the dam throughout the Gazette. There were also only two instances, so it just did not seem appropriate to give its own section,and it fits nowhere better than &amp;ldquo;Other&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I found most interesting was how close the three major topics were in the numberof instances. This really shows that there was not one topic that had more significance than another in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. What it also shows is how significant the dam is to the Gazette. Over the span of about 38 months, it appeared in 117 sections. If it was only mentioned in one section per day without multiples, this would mean it was brought up in 117 days during roughly a 1,140-day period. I do not know exactly how much attention a topic needs to be significant, but I would imagine seeing the dam in about 10% of issues over 4 years is pretty significant. Although I did not collect the dates of all these instances, I noticed that a good number of sections that fell under the &amp;ldquo;government&amp;rdquo; section came in late 1907 and in 1908 after the flooding occurred. This makes me believe that in the issues that come after what I have access to are likely going to include &amp;ldquo;government&amp;rdquo; sections at an increased rate. Most of the sections talked about how the government responded to the flooding, or people writing editorials complaining about the lack of help the government offered before and after the flooding.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A potential future project could be looking at how these instances progressed by year in order to see if there were trends. Perhaps using this chart and making the solid color a gradient based on how many instances each topic saw in a year or month even. Another question I have is wondering if the most significant topic connected to Assouan was not the dam. The most common results are through advertisements and ferries, but I would like to compare the dam topic in its entirety to another topic if there is a major one present.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
