<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Elena Beggs | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/elenabeggs/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/elenabeggs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Elena Beggs</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/elenabeggs/avatar_hu5da1a3994fe0a0b775b79de918c189e0_74056_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Elena Beggs</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/elenabeggs/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudden Death in 20th Century Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-beggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-beggs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I began the research by searching for a correlation between illnesses and patent medicine advertisements. This led me to research the types of illness the medicine advertisements claimed to cure. The final question I decided to research is: whether illnesses mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; are comparable modern illnesses of the same name. I compiled a list of the most common diseases mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, but in the end, catarrh was the sickness about which I was most curious. The three companies I considered were Peruna, Allenburys’, and Dr. William’s Pink Pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Peruna is a very familiar sight in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Overwhelmingly, Peruna promised to cure catarrh and consumption. Peruna referenced catarrh as a sickness, “Peruna is the best remedy for all catarrhal diseases. When the catarrh has become systemic, – that is, when it has been allowed to spread through the entire system, it is a difficult disease to cure” (“PE-RU-NA was successful where doctors failed”, June 26, 1906). By reading the quote from the newspaper, it is apparent that the authors of the advertisement thought of catarrh as a disease. Today, the term catarrh is not as prolific. Its meaning is also more ambiguous. The definition of catarrh according to Merriam-Webster is an “inflammation of a mucous membrane” (Catarrh). Peruna claims catarrh can be of the head, throat, lungs, stomach, kidneys, and pelvic organs. According to the &lt;em&gt;British Medical Journal&lt;/em&gt; from 1859, the symptoms of catarrh are: grit in the eye, headache, impairment of smell, thirst, appetite loss, nausea, and abdominal pain (&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/25193777&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Jones&lt;/a&gt;, p.773). The Sudafed® website lists these symptoms of catarrh: runny nose, headache, face pains, feeling of mucus in the throat, “a reduced sense of smell and taste, temporary hearing loss and a crackling in [the] ear, and a sore, scratchy throat” (&amp;quot;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sudafed.co.uk/what-catarrh-and-how-get-rid-it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;What is Catarrh&lt;/a&gt;&amp;quot;). It is very difficult to find any information about catarrh in a modern sense. These two lists of symptoms are very similar. The main difference is the catarrh mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was much more extensive (affecting all mucous membranes in the body).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The term &amp;ldquo;catarrh&amp;rdquo; is mentioned 728 times in all the digitized copies of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Of the 728 mentions, only four of those mentions were not in advertisements (nearly all of these mentions came from Peruna advertisements but around three came from another patent medicine). One was a sad story about a man suffering from catarrh who committed suicide (not, according to the article, because of the catarrh). The other three mentions remarked about notable personages suffering from catarrh. It seems like the meaning of the disease catarrh changed through the century. Although the term catarrh is uncommon in this region of the world today, when used, it essentially means the same thing it did during the time of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some additional material that I found is lists of diseases within advertisements. While Peruna concentrated on sickness, Allenburys’ appears to be a company that concentrated on supplements or fortifying food, almost like vitamins today. Allenburys’ advertised itself as a restorative medicine, but also as a preventative diet. The most common version of the advertisement was the one summarized as the “Strength and Stamina” advertisement.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Allenburys&amp;amp;rsquo; Advertisement Distribution of Topics&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-beggs/IDS-2681-Analysis-Project-Image-Allenburys%27-Content_hu912ea477f462d0ccd4059162194f1982_38832_4c96b1604492c584c9d83333d6d78093.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-beggs/IDS-2681-Analysis-Project-Image-Allenburys%27-Content_hu912ea477f462d0ccd4059162194f1982_38832_2643658e2efec58cacb4c5b92d93191f.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-beggs/IDS-2681-Analysis-Project-Image-Allenburys%27-Content_hu912ea477f462d0ccd4059162194f1982_38832_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-beggs/IDS-2681-Analysis-Project-Image-Allenburys%27-Content_hu912ea477f462d0ccd4059162194f1982_38832_4c96b1604492c584c9d83333d6d78093.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;693&#34;
               height=&#34;436&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Dr. William&amp;amp;rsquo;s Pink Pills Spreadsheet of Illnesses Mentioned&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-beggs/_hu054a2c7ba11b1242df537fe1174fa9ef_84087_3fb6525923f03617028cbfe016860ab7.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-beggs/_hu054a2c7ba11b1242df537fe1174fa9ef_84087_4af117465bf4ae63cf99548d712436ba.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-beggs/_hu054a2c7ba11b1242df537fe1174fa9ef_84087_fd7e6005751b75e3e77fe3ff7da137a3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-beggs/_hu054a2c7ba11b1242df537fe1174fa9ef_84087_3fb6525923f03617028cbfe016860ab7.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;550&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The last patent medicine considered in this research is Dr. William’s Pink Pills. The most common ailment the Pills claimed to cure was rheumatism followed by anemia, indigestion, and sciatica. As seen in the image above, it seems almost random which disease the advertisement claims to cure each time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I used variations on the following XPath queries to find the data.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,&#39;peruna&#39;, &#39;i&#39;)][@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;]/div&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,&#39;catarrh&#39;, &#39;i&#39;)][not(@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;)]/p&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These queries have problems because the unit &lt;code&gt;[not(@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;)]&lt;/code&gt; is not always reliable. Sometimes a type is not used to define an advertisement. The other difficulty with this research topic is the lack of reliable information on historical illnesses. The reson I chose Peruna, Dr. William&amp;rsquo;s Pink Pills, and Allenburys&amp;rsquo; is they are the most common medicinal advertisements. This topic has many ways to expand upon the small amount of research I completed. Future research could expand upon each disease mentioned in the advertisements. Another idea for future research would be to compare treatment methods of the diseases to modern treatments. This research hardly covered any of the topic. There is much more to discover within the topic of 1900s illnesses and their treatments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jones, C. Handfield. “Catarrh.” The British Medical Journal, vol. 2, no. 143, 1859, pp. 772–76. JSTOR, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.jstor.org/stable/25193777&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.jstor.org/stable/25193777&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 2 Dec. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;What is Catarrh and How to Get Rid of It.&amp;rdquo; Johnson &amp;amp; Johnson (Ireland) Limited. (2022) &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sudafed.co.uk/what-catarrh-and-how-get-rid-it&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.sudafed.co.uk/what-catarrh-and-how-get-rid-it&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed Dec. 2, 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Catarrh.” Merriam-Webster.com Dictionary, Merriam-Webster, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/catarrh&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.merriam-webster.com/dictionary/catarrh&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 2 Dec. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mentions of Disease in the Egyptian Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The question our group sought to answer was how the number of mentions of diseases in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; differs according to when they were discovered. We analyzed the frequency at which 14 different diseases were mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; from January 1905 to December 1907 and compared the results to how recently the disease had been discovered for the people in this time. In order to collect the data on how often specific illnesses were referenced, our group employed the use of both target word searches in the content repository as well as tailored XPath queries. The queries focused on finding mentions of the different diseases. We accounted for spelling differences such as with smallpox by performing multiple queries per disease when necessary (ex. “smallpox” and “small pox”). These word searches produced an information set that revealed mentions by month of Pneumonia, Epilepsy, Smallpox, Yellow fever, Aneurysm, Heart disease, Stroke, Cholera, Bilharzia, Enteritis, Typhoid, Tuberculosis, and Influenza.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the plague, we used the XPath &lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,&#39;plague&#39; ,&#39;i&#39;)]/*[not(matches(.,&#39;cattle&#39;))]/*[not(matches(.,&#39;locust&#39;))]/head&lt;/code&gt;. This specific XPath is designed to find how often Headlines containing the word “plague” are found in the Egyptian Gazette. Not only that, but because we are looking for Sapien incidents, the XPath excluded instances where cattle or locusts were addressed in conjunction with “plague”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One reason we chose the diseases mentioned in this analysis project is because of their application to our projects. However, we also primarily focused our attention on more commonly known diseases of the time, such as plague, cholera, and tuberculosis. We also included data on illnesses like stroke and heart disease in conjunction with contagious diseases. Furthermore, we considered epilepsy as a potential data point but discovered that the newspaper only mentioned it twice. Therefore, our work is not comprehensive of all diseases mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, but it attempts to cover a variety of common and uncommon diseases occurring during that era.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once the data on each disease was collected, it was organized into a list of dates detailing when they were mentioned in the Egyptian Gazette. The data was then separated by month and placed into two bar charts to visualize our findings. One reveals how many mentions there are of the individual diseases each month and separates the findings by color for comparative clarity. The second chart shows the total count of “new diseases” compared to “old diseases” from 1905 to 1907.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For the sake of this analysis, “new diseases” are considered anything discovered within the last century of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; articles being written. “Old diseases” on the other hand are the remaining illnesses, chronic or acute, claimed to have been discovered before the 19th century. This classification system was created to be based on how the readers and authors of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; would have thought of the diseases. While we today may think of diseases like tuberculosis and typhoid as old since they are no longer common, it is important to remember that they were relatively new for the time period in which the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was written.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Graph 1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph1_huc8d50f20816dcc60752eae54b2444f3e_439764_5e7d65026156a83c4a3e63f7b8330cb1.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph1_huc8d50f20816dcc60752eae54b2444f3e_439764_4902c1eb6704ea5c616c51e4862c718e.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph1_huc8d50f20816dcc60752eae54b2444f3e_439764_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph1_huc8d50f20816dcc60752eae54b2444f3e_439764_5e7d65026156a83c4a3e63f7b8330cb1.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;450&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Graph 2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph2_huf008064e2744db31de6b5b208b0febda_411081_f0a021be2ae0ad58557665b7cc01ec79.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph2_huf008064e2744db31de6b5b208b0febda_411081_a83ac11bb6b0227c263f57b4a6011d0a.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph2_huf008064e2744db31de6b5b208b0febda_411081_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph2_huf008064e2744db31de6b5b208b0febda_411081_f0a021be2ae0ad58557665b7cc01ec79.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;460&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Graph 3&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph3_hu586023f21d57631956e7c3da5001be16_641489_f5bab666ec79e54cd9846abfaba3d133.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph3_hu586023f21d57631956e7c3da5001be16_641489_5b6c4fe1aed929425205f8b8479cbc50.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph3_hu586023f21d57631956e7c3da5001be16_641489_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph3_hu586023f21d57631956e7c3da5001be16_641489_f5bab666ec79e54cd9846abfaba3d133.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;434&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That said, several of the diseases we are analyzing have documentation dating back to a thousand years or more before the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was written. For clarity purposes, the first &amp;ldquo;documentation&amp;rdquo; of a disease is defined as the first time it was mentioned in recorded history.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hippocrates recorded the symptoms of a &lt;strong&gt;stroke&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;pneumonia&lt;/strong&gt; during his lifetime, which was from 460-370 BC (Nilsen and Imogen).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aneurysm&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;smallpox&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;plague&lt;/strong&gt; were discovered between 100 AD and 600 AD in the order listed (Livesay, “History of Smallpox”, and “plague”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The first record of &lt;strong&gt;influenza&lt;/strong&gt; was an epidemic in 1173 AD and &lt;strong&gt;yellow fever&lt;/strong&gt; began in the Americas during the 1500s (Shimizu and “yellow fever”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The origin of the concept of &lt;strong&gt;heart disease&lt;/strong&gt; is a bit vague, but in 1768, a speech was given about coronary artery disease (“History of Heart Attack”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cholera&lt;/strong&gt; also has an obscure history because reports of a disease with similar symptoms existed in India thousands of years before the first documentation of it in 1817 (“cholera”).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In 1851, Bilharz found the cause of &lt;strong&gt;bilharzia&lt;/strong&gt; (parasitic worms).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A few years later in 1880, the source of &lt;strong&gt;typhoid&lt;/strong&gt; was discovered (specific bacteria) (Barakat and Marinelli).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Tuberculosis&lt;/strong&gt; was discovered by Dr. Robert Koch in 1854 when he first isolated the bacteria which causes it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enteritis&lt;/strong&gt; was the most recently classified disease (1850-1900) discussed in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; (Kirsner).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite all these reports, unfortunately, sometimes this date is vague and uncertain, and often information about the disease was verbally imparted to the next generation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data reveals that the most commonly mentioned disease was the Plague, with the second most common being cholera. One reason this could be the case is that there may have been more cases of the Plague than Cholera in Alexandria between 1905 and 1907. However, it is important to note that Europe was recovering from a major outbreak of the Plague in 1899, in which 250 cases were recorded. For perspective, this number dropped to less than 20 by 1903. Most of the cases were recorded in coastal and inland port cities such as London, Liverpool, and Marseille. Because Alexandria is a major port city with heavy traffic between these areas, it is likely they would have been concerned with outbreaks in their own city, especially in the wake of a major European pandemic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since mentions of the plague were so prolific, we only included mentions featured in headlines; whereas, for every other disease, we counted the total mentions. Despite these measures, plague still outranked all other diseases at 259 mentions. The disease referenced the second most was cholera at 236 mentions. Furthermore, the diseases mentioned the least were aneurysms (2) and bilharzia (4). Both of these diseases were not featured regularly in the Gazette, potentially due to them being either very rare or so common that they don’t require reporting. Overall, diseases classified as “old” (482 times) were mentioned more than diseases classified as “modern” (304 times), but this figure includes plague, which could be considered an outlier due to its prevalence. When the numbers are analyzed without plague, modern diseases are mentioned more (304 times) compared to old diseases (114 times).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Graph 4&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph4_huae5f8e110a0c85d9a45b8cc896614efc_409671_9f104511493c5900b0b93b455b4ac30f.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph4_huae5f8e110a0c85d9a45b8cc896614efc_409671_2b1516bb10a79f00a1d87bca6de84a9c.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph4_huae5f8e110a0c85d9a45b8cc896614efc_409671_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph4_huae5f8e110a0c85d9a45b8cc896614efc_409671_9f104511493c5900b0b93b455b4ac30f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;459&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Graph 5&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph5_hu787130204881641eefe0cd7330069e68_458007_1cd1611087decec5058e75fd2da417d2.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph5_hu787130204881641eefe0cd7330069e68_458007_0c250dbeff097580a7aa59cde57589db.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph5_hu787130204881641eefe0cd7330069e68_458007_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-disease-group/Graph5_hu787130204881641eefe0cd7330069e68_458007_1cd1611087decec5058e75fd2da417d2.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;442&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also, for most of the diseases, there were no predictable or seasonal trends. The plague was an exception to this rule and experienced an increase in mentions during the summer months. The fluctuation could be the result of conflicting attitudes toward quarantine practices, or the product of preexisting outbreak fears that increased during the summer and fall months. Another explanation is that case numbers did actually increase during these months despite anecdotal and historical claims to the contrary. The data itself could also be flawed and not accurately reflect the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;’s true contents. For the other diseases, the lack of a pattern could be due to many elements. This study examines the mentions of disease, not the actual case numbers, so the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; could have not mentioned cases for a variety of reasons. Cholera, on the other hand, remained fairly consistent and level in its number of mentions, but there were 2 spikes in the data that serve as staggering outliers. These spikes occurred in September 1905 and January 1908. Cholera is transmitted through contaminated food or water, so, in a time when sanitation was lacking, it was a very transmissible disease. As a result, a possible reason for the spikes could be cholera outbreaks. Further investigation into the articles where the mentions are found confirms this theory, with both spikes being caused by increased reporting on widespread outbreaks. This finding also creates the idea that perhaps the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; prefers to report on large disease clusters and not individual cases, adding another layer to why certain diseases are mentioned less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, the data chart shows that the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; mentioned old diseases more often than new ones. There are many potential theories for why this is the case. First, modern diseases were much less known among the public. Many of the “old” diseases had been identifiable for centuries, so it makes sense that they were recognized by the population sufficiently enough to get reported on by the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Modern diseases might have been equally prevalent among the populations, but if they were not known formally by most of the population, their numbers would have been difficult to report. Additionally, the category of &amp;ldquo;old diseases&amp;rsquo;&amp;rsquo; includes the plague, which is the most commonly mentioned disease. If plague were to be excluded from the data as an outlier, modern diseases would be mentioned more than old diseases. A possible reason for this is that many of the modern diseases were highly contagious, such as cholera and influenza. Since these diseases lend themselves to outbreaks, it makes sense that they would be mentioned more than others. As the 2020 COVID-19 Pandemic has revealed, outbreaks have the potential to get a lot of media attention. Another theory for the prevalence of modern diseases is precisely because they are &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo;. While the relatively recent discovery of these diseases would result in them being less recognized, it could also prompt the Gazette to mention them more frequently to alert, educate, or attract curious readers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the end, many factors could have influenced the data reflected in our initial query, and there is no definitive way to isolate one, if any, as the true cause. Still, further research on this project could include analyzing the changes and trends in how the media discusses diseases over the next century. By expanding the data set, an explanation might emerge as the most likely for the discrepancies. As &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; diseases become “old” and as scientific understandings of illnesses increase, one could explore how news organizations choose to talk about diseases, and what the influencing factors of this type of media content are. Are they similar to the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in 1905, or do they reveal a greater shift in public perceptions of chronic and acute diseases?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barakat, Rashida M R. “Epidemiology of Schistosomiasis in Egypt: Travel through Time: Review.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of advanced research&lt;/em&gt; vol. 4,5 (2013): 425-32. doi:10.1016/j.jare.2012.07.003&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Barbara, Bramanti, et al. “The Third Plague Pandemic in Europe.” &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the Royal Society B: Biological Sciences&lt;/em&gt;, 17 Apr. 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rspb.2018.2429&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://royalsocietypublishing.org/doi/10.1098/rspb.2018.2429&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britannica, The Information Architects of Encyclopaedia. &amp;ldquo;cholera&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;Encyclopedia Britannica&lt;/em&gt;, 18 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/facts/cholera&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/facts/cholera&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britannica, The Information Architects of Encyclopaedia. &amp;ldquo;plague&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;Encyclopedia Britannica&lt;/em&gt;, 18 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/facts/plague&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/facts/plague&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 Nov. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Britannica, The Information Architects of Encyclopaedia. &amp;ldquo;yellow fever&amp;rdquo;. &lt;em&gt;Encyclopedia Britannica&lt;/em&gt;, 18 Nov. 2022, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.britannica.com/facts/yellow-fever&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.britannica.com/facts/yellow-fever&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 November 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gerard, Imogen and Root, Kelsie. “Pneumonia.” University of Leeds, 2017, &lt;a href=&#34;https://library.leeds.ac.uk/special-collections/collection/2149/pneumonia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://library.leeds.ac.uk/special-collections/collection/2149/pneumonia&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 Nov. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“History of Heart Attack: Diagnosis and Understanding”.  University of Minnesota, 15 Oct. 2012. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.epi.umn.edu/cvdepi/essay/history-of-heart-attack-diagnosis-and-understanding/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;http://www.epi.umn.edu/cvdepi/essay/history-of-heart-attack-diagnosis-and-understanding/&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 Nov. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“History of Smallpox.” Centers for Disease Control and Prevention, 20 Feb. 2021, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/smallpox/history/history.html&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.cdc.gov/smallpox/history/history.html&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 Nov. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kirsner, J B. “Historical aspects of inflammatory bowel disease.” &lt;em&gt;Journal of clinical gastroenterology&lt;/em&gt; vol. 10,3 (1988): 286-97. doi:10.1097/00004836-198806000-00012&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Livesay, James J et al. “Milestones in the treatment of aortic aneurysm: Denton A. Cooley, MD, and the Texas Heart Institute.” Texas Heart Institute journal vol. 32,2 (2005): 130-4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Marineli, Filio et al. “Mary Mallon (1869-1938) and the history of typhoid fever.” &lt;em&gt;Annals of gastroenterology&lt;/em&gt; vol. 26,2 (2013): 132-134.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Nilsen, Marci Lee. “A historical account of stroke and the evolution of nursing care for stroke patients.” &lt;em&gt;The Journal of neuroscience nursing : journal of the American Association of Neuroscience Nurses&lt;/em&gt; vol. 42,1 (2010): 19-27. doi:10.1097/jnn.0b013e3181c1fdad&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Shimizu, K. Nihon rinsho. &lt;em&gt;Japanese journal of clinical medicine&lt;/em&gt; vol. 55,10 (1997): 2505-11.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Tuberculosis (TB): History”. Centers for Disease Control and Prevention. 12 Dec. 2016. &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.cdc.gov/tb/worldtbday/history.htm&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.cdc.gov/tb/worldtbday/history.htm&lt;/a&gt;. Accessed 18 Nov. 2022.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sudden Death</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-24-beggs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-24-beggs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;image&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-10-24-beggs/featured_hu8bc2f6d70dd1507d3fbca7406687f8fb_183611_e23e55fc77d9ba881dbd51c9d9c8512e.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-10-24-beggs/featured_hu8bc2f6d70dd1507d3fbca7406687f8fb_183611_61c8bb35daec0e3992ac2b484c70e010.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-10-24-beggs/featured_hu8bc2f6d70dd1507d3fbca7406687f8fb_183611_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-24-beggs/featured_hu8bc2f6d70dd1507d3fbca7406687f8fb_183611_e23e55fc77d9ba881dbd51c9d9c8512e.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;757&#34;
               height=&#34;231&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section of &lt;em&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, different articles on death occur often. While others have researched the &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;plague&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/19-analysis-himmel/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;cholera&lt;/a&gt;, I was intrigued by the term sudden death. The “Local and General” and “Personal and Social” sections of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; mentions sudden death many times. Typically, the news reports about sudden deaths give information about a random person. This is an example from a 1905 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, “Mustafa Mohamed el Deep, a native butcher of 50 years of, suddenly fell dead in a tramcar yesterday. His death is reported to been caused by heart failure” (1905-10-12, “Sudden Death”). Historically, how much information did the medical community have in the early 1900s concerning sudden death?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1908, Theodore Fisher, M.D., F.R.C.P. published a book titled &lt;a href=&#34;https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=hvd.hc2dq8&amp;amp;view=1up&amp;amp;seq=9&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Heart and Sudden Death&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. This publication presents an abundance of information about the heart and heart diseases. The book describes aneurisms, alcoholism and the heart, and many more topics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most of the stories in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; that have a diagnosis fall into the category of heart failure, heart disease, or natural causes. Some other causes included ruptured aneurisms and apoplexy. The definition of apoplexy according to &lt;em&gt;A Dictionary of Medical Science&lt;/em&gt; published in 1903 is: “interstitial hemorrhage; effusion of blood occurring suddenly into the substance of an organ or tissue, as the brain, lung, etc.” This definition also makes clear that apoplexy is not cerebral hemorrhage which accounted for the cause of one of the deaths recorded in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although the reports of sudden death in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; seem slightly out of place to modern readers, it must have been important to the colonists then. Medical knowledge was expanding rapidly in the nineteenth and twentieth centuries, for example, in 1901 Karl Landsteiner discovered different blood types. At this point in time, physicians knew a great deal about the causes of heart disease although they knew little about how to prevent it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
