<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>plague | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/plague/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/plague/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>plague</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/plague/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cattle Plague in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-29-sharrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-29-sharrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-caption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cattle Plague&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_42328e87bc921f65f80fc3f763a186cc.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_451f8bae38a021ce9b5e40f537a25212.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_42328e87bc921f65f80fc3f763a186cc.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;669&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Caption
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I began the research process, I constantly ran into information about various plagues: specifically the Bubonic Plague. What appeared less frequently, however, was cattle plague. Upon seeing an excerpt on page 3 of the 1904-12-16 issue of The Egyptian Gazette, I delved deeper. What is &amp;ldquo;bovine typhus&amp;rdquo; and why was it important to the readers of The Egyptian Gazette?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rinderpest&#34;&gt;Rinderpest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cattle Plague, also known as Rinderpest, entered Africa in the 1880s most likely from the shipment of cattle from Arabia or Bombay. Many Egyptians urged the government to take action against this through trade restrictions; however, the Egyptian government needed to import cattle to have enough for the country. Instead, the government set up a quarantine site for any cattle and sheep entering the country. Despite their efforts, the plague entered Egypt in 1903 due to a lack of knowledge about the symptoms in bovine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The epidemic&amp;rsquo;s effects were disastrous in Egypt. Symptoms included diarrhea, high fever, oral erosions, lymphoid necrosis, etc. Many cattle met their demise. According to The Egyptian Gazette, as of 1904-12-16, an estimated 146,649 cattle had died from the plague. This explains the significance of the coverage in the newspaper. It is important to the readers of the paper to understand the status of the cattle plague so they can keep their bovine healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-egyptian-gazette&#34;&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became curious about what section of The Egyptian Gazette the cattle plague appeared in most frequently, so I ran a simple Xpath Query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(., &#39;cattle plague&#39;, &#39;i&#39;)]/@feature&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This searched for the term &amp;ldquo;cattle plague&amp;rdquo; within any feature of The Egyptian Gazette. It returned 68 hits, and I found that the cattle plague appeared most in the Local and General sections of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-links&#34;&gt;additional links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ia800708.us.archive.org/view_archive.php?archive=/22/items/crossref-pre-1909-scholarly-works/10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252804%252980032-8.zip&amp;amp;file=10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252805%252980072-4.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ia800708.us.archive.org/view_archive.php?archive=/22/items/crossref-pre-1909-scholarly-works/10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252804%252980032-8.zip&amp;file=10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252805%252980072-4.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03670074.1960.11665255?journalCode=teaf19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03670074.1960.11665255?journalCode=teaf19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-1-4419-8901-7_1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-1-4419-8901-7_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-vazquez/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-vazquez/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-medina/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-medina/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bubonic Plague&#39;s Continuation Into the 20th Century</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;While encoding my 1906-10-17 issue of the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I was enthralled by mention of the bubonic plague in the “Local and General” section. The bubonic plague is a bacterial infection commonly carried by fleas and rats that causes fever, swollen lymph nodes, and even gangrene in the extremities, hence its nickname the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2090123213001380&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;Black death&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt;. I was familiar with this plague’s epidemic in Western Europe during the 14th century, but I had not realized that the plague continued to infect humans. Upon further research, I learned that there was &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0033350607000145&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;a second epidemic of the bubonic plague in India&lt;/a&gt; throughout the 19th and 20th centuries for about five decades. Cases of bubonic plague persist around the world &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic.oup.com/cid/article/49/5/736/308284&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;still even to this day&lt;/a&gt;, which I found particularly intriguing; it completely dumbfounded my previous notions that the plague no longer existed. Specifically in the context of Egypt in the early 20th century, I learned from &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/17-analysis-migdalski/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;past student blog posts&lt;/a&gt; that the plague was most prevalent in 1904, followed by an immediate, drastic decrease in 1905. In fact, there was a bulletin posted in October of 1905 that read &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-eugenio/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&amp;ldquo;NO MORE PLAGUE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a&gt; Within just two years, the total cases dropped to zero, which I found compelling considering the plague’s reputation of spreading viscously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Image label&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_26f861be725f8c5c82c675772cbda8fd.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_8414a6c43948a1f265daeb0ab33c2691.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_26f861be725f8c5c82c675772cbda8fd.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;229&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My issue’s report of the plague’s reappearance further complicates the issue of the bubonic plague in early 20th century Egypt; what allowed the plague to dwindle down and reappear? What specific conditions fostered an epidemic in India but not in Egypt when they were dealing with the same disease? These are questions that microhistorical data in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; can help answer. I also think it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the afflicted person in this bulletin was a waiter, meaning he had ample opportunity to transmit the disease to countless other people. A later issue in the same month of that year revealed that there had been 500 cases from January to October in 1906, which is a stark increase from the supposedly zero cases in 1905; this all leads me to conclude that this case of plague was not rare for the time, and that the plague reappeared with a vigor. I wonder, too, if there was any significance to the newspaper mentioning that he was Greek; was this their way of racializing the disease? Upon looking futher into the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I discovered a trend in reporting individual cases of the bubonic plague with little to no detail in the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section. In issues &lt;a href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/1905-page-images-1/1905-01-13-p3.jpg&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;like this one&lt;/a&gt;, the bulletins were only concerned with sharing the numbers of cases and the deaths. (In this issue, the &amp;ldquo;Bubonic Plague&amp;rdquo; bulletin is in the third column.) Rarely did they report the occupation or ethnicity of someone afflicted, which makes this particular bulletin all the more interesting and worthy of research.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Death amongst the Egyptians</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-chapple/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-chapple/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On October 16, 1906 there have been multiple reports if incidents of the Bubonique Plague and Typhoid Fever. Citizens are dying at an alarming rate and there has reportedly been an outbreak on a steamship that was set to sail to Ras-el-Tin. A first class domestic man by the name of R. Cole sailing on H.M.S Venus was suffering from symptoms of &amp;ldquo;interior fever&amp;rdquo; and was rushed to the hospital immediately after disembarking the ship. Mr. Cole tragically succumbed to his illness at 2.45am on October 16.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A second case of typhoid fever occurred on board the Venus since her arrival of Egyptian waters. The first person to experience symptoms was Captain Eyre, who has since been rushed to a hospital in Port Said.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The week prior to October 15, there have been a report of 6 cases of the Bubonique Plague throughout the country of Egypt, 3 cases at Alexandria, 2 at Suez, and one in the Minieh district. This is alarming as 492 cases have been reported since the start of the year, and this is a large increase from the previous year of 1905 where 264 incidents had been reported.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-migdalski-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-23-migdalski-plague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this short newspaper article on the third page of the first day of my issue, the topic was about a plague outbreak that had numerous cases throughout Egypt. Victims of the plague had been reported dead in a number of villages.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The article states some, but not all, of the cases were said to be pneumonic, which means it affected the lungs. This creates a curiosity for me. If only the majority of the deaths were caused by pneumonia, I wonder if all of the people who died, were infected by the same disease.  I am also curious if the disease affected different people in different ways. The article explicitly states that they deemed this plague to be contracted through direct contact. I am curious as to the origins of this plague and the characteristics and symptoms of it as well. I searched for outside information regarding this plague and &lt;a href=&#34;https://books.google.com/books?id=r_YDAAAAYAAJ&amp;amp;pg=PA3&amp;amp;lpg=PA3&amp;amp;dq=plague&amp;#43;in&amp;#43;egypt&amp;#43;1906&amp;amp;source=bl&amp;amp;ots=HqzdiEyewX&amp;amp;sig=7Ev85udX7QZKFaTyZEzkBb7ZukY&amp;amp;hl=en&amp;amp;sa=X&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwjD79H4pMLSAhXEOSYKHcjnDo4Q6AEIIjAB#v=onepage&amp;amp;q=plague%20in%20egypt%201906&amp;amp;f=false&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt;explains that this plague had affected other countries as well such as India, South America, and Europe.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, the article talks about improvements made in a village where numerous cases of the plague occurred as well as providing treatment to one infected patient that led to their cure. This proves that the medical professionals of Egypt were able to identify the disease and develop a treatment that helped cure at least one patient. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ancient.eu/article/51/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This website&lt;/a&gt; explains how diseases were treated in ancient Egypt. People were still exposed to similar diseases that are found today, however, their treatment methods were much different. They used medicines and &amp;ldquo;magic&amp;rdquo; which referred to asking the gods for treatment. They also made their own medical remedies, many of which contained beer which was believed to have powerful curing effects. I am interested to know how they treated and cured the single patient.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Additionally, medical practices in ancient Egypt have a lasting effect on present methods. Through further research, &lt;a href=&#34;https://explorable.com/ancient-medicine&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;this website&lt;/a&gt; went into detail on how treatments in ancient Egypt influenced treatments used today. For example, ancient Egyptian professionals used various herbs to create medicines to cure diseases and sicknesses. Many of these same remedies are still used today. Ancient medical practices were more advanced than I presumed. There is evidence that Egyptian doctors performed eye surgery, dentistry, used prosthetics, healed broken bones, and more. Many of their treatment and healing methods were published in books that are still being preserved today. It is interesting that medical practices used in ancient times are still being used in one way or another in modern times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A number of my classmates and students in the past also inquired questions regarding the plague. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/rymer-plague/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;One student&lt;/a&gt; was also curious to know more about the plague, its origins, symptoms, and treatment. I searched through various blog posts that were written on the plague and noticed a trend. Multiple students were wondering why there was not much information on the plague. &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Corzo-TheSilentKiller/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This student&lt;/a&gt; wrote about the small number of reports that were made about the plague. In my issue there was only one small article hidden on the third page. This makes me question how serious the disease was at the time and if it was something that either was not a major threat or if it was being hidden from the public. This is something I hope to learn more about as I continue working with my week.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I continue to go through my week in this newspaper, I hope to find more information about this plague. I wonder if the number of deaths will decreases and if a fully effective cure is developed to prevent further infections.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Plague</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-14-rymer-plague/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-14-rymer-plague/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Reports of a plague should be announced far and wide, so why is it that the Egyptian Gazette practically buried this news in the middle of the page?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On August 23, 1905, the Egyptian Gazette reported the new of a plague hitting citizens of Alexandria.  Sounds like big news right? In present time, news of a local plague would cover the headlines.  One would think it would as well in 1905; however, the Gazette reported the plague in the middle of page 3, between a headline of stray dogs and the opening of a new school.  Why did this news simply seem to just pass through the cracks of a newspaper and make it on the publication?  Is it possible the newspaper didn’t want people to know about the plague? Was this type of affliction so common in 1905 that it didn’t even phase the subscribers? In either case, it seems to be a pretty harsh place to live in compared to modern standards.  Either this newspaper overlooks the safety of its subscribers heavily, or a plague infection wasn’t even a big enough deal at the time to turn the heads of the common Egyptian.  Its hard to believe a plague would go by so nonchalantly.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
