<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>health | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/health/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/health/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>health</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>health</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/health/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cattle Plague in Egypt</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-29-sharrow/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-29-sharrow/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-caption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Cattle Plague&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_42328e87bc921f65f80fc3f763a186cc.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_451f8bae38a021ce9b5e40f537a25212.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-29-sharrow/featured_hu517b9e61da6e4c6d4dc939968c50f745_673497_42328e87bc921f65f80fc3f763a186cc.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;669&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Caption
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As I began the research process, I constantly ran into information about various plagues: specifically the Bubonic Plague. What appeared less frequently, however, was cattle plague. Upon seeing an excerpt on page 3 of the 1904-12-16 issue of The Egyptian Gazette, I delved deeper. What is &amp;ldquo;bovine typhus&amp;rdquo; and why was it important to the readers of The Egyptian Gazette?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rinderpest&#34;&gt;Rinderpest&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Cattle Plague, also known as Rinderpest, entered Africa in the 1880s most likely from the shipment of cattle from Arabia or Bombay. Many Egyptians urged the government to take action against this through trade restrictions; however, the Egyptian government needed to import cattle to have enough for the country. Instead, the government set up a quarantine site for any cattle and sheep entering the country. Despite their efforts, the plague entered Egypt in 1903 due to a lack of knowledge about the symptoms in bovine.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The epidemic&amp;rsquo;s effects were disastrous in Egypt. Symptoms included diarrhea, high fever, oral erosions, lymphoid necrosis, etc. Many cattle met their demise. According to The Egyptian Gazette, as of 1904-12-16, an estimated 146,649 cattle had died from the plague. This explains the significance of the coverage in the newspaper. It is important to the readers of the paper to understand the status of the cattle plague so they can keep their bovine healthy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-egyptian-gazette&#34;&gt;The Egyptian Gazette&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I became curious about what section of The Egyptian Gazette the cattle plague appeared in most frequently, so I ran a simple Xpath Query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(., &#39;cattle plague&#39;, &#39;i&#39;)]/@feature&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This searched for the term &amp;ldquo;cattle plague&amp;rdquo; within any feature of The Egyptian Gazette. It returned 68 hits, and I found that the cattle plague appeared most in the Local and General sections of the paper.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;additional-links&#34;&gt;additional links&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://ia800708.us.archive.org/view_archive.php?archive=/22/items/crossref-pre-1909-scholarly-works/10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252804%252980032-8.zip&amp;amp;file=10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252805%252980072-4.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://ia800708.us.archive.org/view_archive.php?archive=/22/items/crossref-pre-1909-scholarly-works/10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252804%252980032-8.zip&amp;file=10.1016%252Fs0368-1742%252805%252980072-4.pdf&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03670074.1960.11665255?journalCode=teaf19&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.tandfonline.com/doi/abs/10.1080/03670074.1960.11665255?journalCode=teaf19&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-1-4419-8901-7_1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://link.springer.com/chapter/10.1007/978-1-4419-8901-7_1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-vazquez/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-vazquez/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-medina/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-medina/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Disease Disparities in the Gazette</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-dininger/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-dininger/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As in all newspapers, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is no stranger to reporting on disease cases. From 1905-1907, the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; mentions various diseases 1,688 times. Despite this large figure, the specific breakdown of which diseases are mentioned more often than others reveals a vast inequality in the amount of mentions per disease. To gather this data, I performed several Xpath queries to determine the number of mentions of different diseases in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, both in total and over time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’plague’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’bilharzia’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’pneumonia’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’small pox’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’tuberculosis’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’cholera’, ‘i’)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This contrast in mentions is immediately obvious upon viewing the data, and raises several questions of why the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; chose its content in this way. This analysis will attempt to explain these disparities in context of when the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was written, and who it was written for.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-total-mentions-of-many-of-the-diseases-in-the-_gazette_&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart1_hu39282c27c6a51df6685fdb3586c52984_48864_8cc14a4e6b6ff1028a87faf35dafc49c.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart1_hu39282c27c6a51df6685fdb3586c52984_48864_9bf3667037a9554413048eb5341d8924.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart1_hu39282c27c6a51df6685fdb3586c52984_48864_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart1_hu39282c27c6a51df6685fdb3586c52984_48864_8cc14a4e6b6ff1028a87faf35dafc49c.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;512&#34;
               height=&#34;316&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Total mentions of many of the diseases in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-total-mentions-of-many-of-the-diseases-in-the-_gazette_-by-month-over-time&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart2_hu0d895a95d339cfbe060f01d81197a977_31554_9af1402dfb70d98f57af0ffdcc2d3d83.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart2_hu0d895a95d339cfbe060f01d81197a977_31554_40cfd54460b35a9d3a2b6bcba7fa8abd.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart2_hu0d895a95d339cfbe060f01d81197a977_31554_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-dininger/chart2_hu0d895a95d339cfbe060f01d81197a977_31554_9af1402dfb70d98f57af0ffdcc2d3d83.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;512&#34;
               height=&#34;317&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Total mentions of many of the diseases in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; by month over time.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Founded in 1880, the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was a newspaper written by British citizens who had moved to Egypt. Early on, it “became the mouthpiece for British policy in Egypt” and was heavily monitored by Lord Cromer, the British Controller-General (Carcanague). Cromer had a large role in the control of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, and it is suspected that he personally subsidized the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. As Controller-General, Cromer was responsible for the administration of Egypt while under British control from 1883-1907 (Lockman).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All this to say that the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; was a distinctly British entity, written by the British, for the British, and containing British opinions. The reason why this is important is that the motivations of the authors of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; are directly related to their audience: British subjects. As emphasized in journalism, one of the key hallmarks of success in the news industry is to know your audience, and write about issues that they have an interest in (Santiago). In the case of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, this means that they were tasked with writing about issues that their fellow British subjects in Egypt were interested in, all while keeping in line with Cromer’s interests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The importance of the audience of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; is crucial to understanding the disparities between which diseases they featured in their issues. Since it was written for British citizens, one can assume that they tended to focus on diseases that tended to impact that population the most. This assumption is not made blindly; it is supported by a comparison of the disease mentions to actual cases during this time period.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the largest cases of the gap between cases and coverage pertains to the disease bilharzia. In her chapter analysis “Cruel Summer,” historian Jennifer Derr provides an account focusing on the prevalence of parasitic diseases, and how new methods of agriculture caused them to become quite common in society (Derr). One of the principal diseases caused by these parasites was schistosomiasis, or as it was referred to in the 1900s, bilharzia. One of the key takeaways from Derr is just how widespread these parasites were in Egypt in this time period, with her stating that the “majority of the populations with regions with access to perennial irrigation” were afflicted. This issue was not something unknown to wider Egypt either; as early as 1838, Italian physician Angelo Dubini identified parasitic worms in the autopsies of Egyptians. These discoveries eventually morphed into scientific investigations of this issue as the 1800s progressed, even getting attention from the Sanitary Department. Derr’s analysis establishes two facts critical to the disparities in attention of diseases: bilharzia was very widespread during this time period and it had been identified as a disease decades prior.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Because of these facts, one might wonder why bilharzia is only mentioned in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; a measly four times over the course of 1905-1907 as revealed by an Xpath query. A potential answer to this issue relates back to the audience of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. While bilharzia was extremely widespread, it was primarily found among Egyptian agricultural workers spending their time in wet, irrigated fields where the parasites easily spread. Since we have already established that the audience of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; would not have been these workers, it stands to reason that it was neglected due to being seen as an Egyptian problem. Compare the 4 mentions of bilharzia to the 1,270 mentions of the plague. Being that the disease killed ⅓ of Europe in the 1300s, all Europeans were quite familiar with the risk of the plague and the knowledge that it was highly contagious. While it certainly did see a high case number during this period, bilharzia did as well, and yet received 318% fewer mentions. This suggests that the audience of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; had a much higher interest in reading about plague than bilharzia. Therefore, the context of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;’s author and audience could have quite plausibly played into what content they chose to focus on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;An additional investigation I conducted was to analyze the mentions of different diseases restricted to advertisements. I chose advertisements because they reflect public consumption and which issues are being emphasized by both consumers and suppliers. The XPath query for this question restricted the results to those labeled as “advert”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This revealed the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;typhoid&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;smallpox&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;small pox&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;pneumonia&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;plague&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;bilharzia)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div[@type=&amp;quot;advert&amp;quot;][contains(., &#39;tuberculosis&#39;)]&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-total-mentions-of-many-of-the-diseases-in-the-_gazette_-by-month-over-time&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;3&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/pic3_hu16e7f3849fc09c69dfd7c4df1c7826f8_16454_31f99b399a9deffd8607981a219cb3c6.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/pic3_hu16e7f3849fc09c69dfd7c4df1c7826f8_16454_0274f9e9231526925b1f36eb6212d436.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-dininger/pic3_hu16e7f3849fc09c69dfd7c4df1c7826f8_16454_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-dininger/pic3_hu16e7f3849fc09c69dfd7c4df1c7826f8_16454_31f99b399a9deffd8607981a219cb3c6.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;512&#34;
               height=&#34;317&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Total mentions of many of the diseases in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; by month over time.
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Interestingly enough, despite having far fewer total mentions than several other diseases, tuberculosis had the most mentions in the advertisement section. These results could have resulted from many factors, including poor knowledge of medicine at the time. However, the 0 mentions of bilharzia echo bilharzia’s few overall mentions and add to the idea that it was neglected by the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;works-cited&#34;&gt;Works Cited:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Carcanague, Marc. &lt;em&gt;Death at Denshawai: a Case Study in the History of British Imperialism in Egypt&lt;/em&gt;. 2020. Capstone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Derr, Jennifer. &lt;em&gt;The Lived Nile: Environment, Disease, and Material Colonial Economy in Egypt&lt;/em&gt;. Stanford University Press, 2019.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Lockman, Zachary. &amp;ldquo;Lord Cromer: Victorian Imperialist, Edwardian Proconsul.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;The Center for Middle Eastern Studies&lt;/em&gt;, Harvard University, 23 May 2006, cmes.fas.harvard.edu/news/lord-cromer-victorian-imperialist-edwardian-proconsul.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Santiago, Anthony. &amp;ldquo;Why Knowing Your Audience is Important for Your Press Release.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Newswire&lt;/em&gt;, 4 Mar. 2019, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.newswire.com/blog/why-knowing-your-audience-is-important-for-your-press-release&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;www.newswire.com/blog/why-knowing-your-audience-is-important-for-your-press-release&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Pills: Stronger Than Death</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-16-phuong/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-16-phuong/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Pills and medicines have relentlessly shown themselves throughout the Egyptian Gazette as miraculous solutions to peoples&amp;rsquo; problems. This piece called &amp;ldquo;STRONGER THAN DEATH&amp;rdquo; begins with stating its purpose: to add more evidence that Pink Pills work. The story of a woman&amp;rsquo;s tragedy plays out in which she develops accumulating sickness after having many children in a short span of time. The sickness only worsens as she finds out her husband had died falling, trying to get out of a tram car in America. The story goes on with how she healed to the point of full health after discovering the existence of the pills.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To me, this article seems to be more about promoting an idea than a real cure. What offsets its validity as a medicine is the idea that it could cure numerous types of sicknesses. &amp;ldquo;They cure anaemia, chlorosis, general debility, stom-ach complaints, rheumatism and neurasthenia.&amp;rdquo; Targeting the population, it uses several tactics. The article appeals to the entire audience, saying &amp;ldquo;Everyone must agree&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;they will do for everybody&amp;rdquo; and more. The article uses a relatable and pained main character that the people would feel sorry for, appealing to human emotions when the descriptions of her life and tragedies such as her husband dying.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;From this instance one learns what Pink Pills can achieve for the weak and enfeebled.&amp;rdquo; This statement paints the pill as a wondrous cure that saves people from weakness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I found was that these stories of the use of phenomenal Pink Pills may be continuous and confirm their worth. In this &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;blog post&lt;/a&gt;, it is revealed that the pill has before already been called &amp;ldquo;Pink Pills are said to cure Anaemia, Indigestion, Eczema, Rheumatism, Sciatica, St. Vitus’ Dance, Neuralgia, Nervous Disorders, Paralysis, and Locomotor Ataxy.&amp;rdquo; This article &amp;ldquo;STRONGER THAN DEATH&amp;rdquo; links back to that with the mention of some of those same sicknesses. The author gives more depth to the pill&amp;rsquo;s contents and how the pills are a scam.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Sultan&#39;s Kidney Disease</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the month of September issues of the Egyptian Gazette, the newspaper talks about the Sultan&#39;s illness. Specifically, in page three of the September 21st issue of 1906, the Sultan is mentioned and the author says he has Bright&#39;s disease. &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bright%27s_disease&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;This disease was named after Richard Bright, a physician.&lt;/a&gt; It was a disease pertaining to the kidney, but was later discovered to be a classification of a variety of kidney diseases that were unknown at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-a-kidney-with-brights-disease&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Brights-Disease&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/kidney_huea17c4cce59483467cece57183a5f2e6_6361_6e8dd4723f94ad884db10a97ea4936bf.webp 400w,
               /post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/kidney_huea17c4cce59483467cece57183a5f2e6_6361_759df92ff580e6f0613c77a6bd95f13c.webp 760w,
               /post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/kidney_huea17c4cce59483467cece57183a5f2e6_6361_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2019-12-13-jimmymendez/kidney_huea17c4cce59483467cece57183a5f2e6_6361_6e8dd4723f94ad884db10a97ea4936bf.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;186&#34;
               height=&#34;271&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      A kidney with Bright&amp;rsquo;s Disease
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A patient with this disease could experience swelling, convulsions, blindness, and coma. A lot of patients with this disease may have also had high blood pressure, heart disease, or diabetes. The newspaper mentions Dr. Nafiz, and Dr. Noureddin Pasha as the primary physicians of the Sultan, but it mentions that they had to consult Professor Bergmann for assistance. Bergmann was the one to diagnose the Sultan with Bright&#39;s disease, and ordered an immediate surgical operation. He also says that he is suffering from &amp;quot;other complications,&amp;quot; which may be anything from diabetes to heart disease to kidney failure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://web.archive.org/web/20160915235645/https:/www.guideline.gov/summaries/summary/36900&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Today, a patient with the same symptoms would be likely diagnosed with chronic nephritis, which is an inflammation of the kidney.&lt;/a&gt; However, in the Thursday issue, it is mentioned that the Sultan was suffering from a stone. This means that he may have had a urinary tract infection. The most common cause of a UTI is  Escherichia coli, or similar fungi. Other causes may include genetic predisposition or being uncircumcised. What exactly caused the Sultan to be ill is unknown, however, the diagnosis at the time was based on similar cases. Richard Bright attributed the disease to high blood pressure and diabetes, which could have been true in the Sultan&#39;s case, as he mourned the recent death of two high functionaries, one of which &amp;quot;enjoyed his majesty&#39;s confidence.&amp;quot;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pink Pills for Pale People</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-blog-wallace/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the age of clickbait, tabloid papers, and fake news, it&amp;rsquo;s still nice to see that we haven&amp;rsquo;t changed a bit. This is a classic example of a snake oil salesmen at work. Dr. Williams&amp;rsquo; Pink Pills are said to cure Anaemia, Indigestion, Eczema, Rheumatism, Sciatica, St. Vitus’ Dance, Neuralgia, Nervous Disorders, Paralysis, and Locomotor Ataxy. Since the pills did have ferrous sulphate or just Iron sulphate, it would have an effect on the anemic. This however, is still a scam because the amount that was in his pink pills was much less than actual medicine and because of this, the pills were much weaker and were more expensive than just the regular iron pills doctors would usually prescribe. This is probably one of the only pills that are in song, while the song is a critique of commercialism in society, it was sung by &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Wu2V3TkHufA&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Benny Bell&lt;/a&gt;. Also something that intrigued me was that you can still &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.springbokpharmacy.co.za/Product?product_id=354130&amp;amp;category_id=33098&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;buy these pills&lt;/a&gt; online to cure basically anything!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A more &lt;a href=&#34;https://diseasesofmodernlife.org/2016/11/29/pills-for-our-ills-dr-williams-pink-pills-for-pale-people/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;elaborate backstory&lt;/a&gt; of the company and pills, as well as how they fared in Asian markets.
[Pink Pills](1907-05-20-p5 selection)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This trend of snake oil pills being sold in The Egyptian Gazette is not a new one. Looking through other blog posts I saw a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/Esteve-Medicine/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;listing&lt;/a&gt; about &amp;ldquo;Doan&amp;rsquo;s Backache Kidney Pills&amp;rdquo;. The man who used it was told he only had 3 months to live but after some pills, he made a miraculous recovery! Another post follows the same vein of a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/curiosities/baxter-Peruna/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;miraculous medicine&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
