<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>williamcrawford | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/williamcrawford/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/williamcrawford/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>williamcrawford</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>williamcrawford</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/williamcrawford/</link></image><item><title>XML encoding in Finereader</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-05-crawford-technical-post/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-12-05-crawford-technical-post/</guid><description>&lt;p>Balancing a logical, accessible, and user friendly xml-encodation of the Egyptian Gazette with preserving its historical visual format is a delicate enterprise. I initially tried to do this with a plaintext editor, and later directly within the Oxygen program itself. I found myself constantly switching between windows on my computer, going back and forth and then back again between the image of the page and the xml-in-progress. By chance, I had to go and re-OCR a page three about a month into the class, and discovered something that greatly decreased the time it took me to structure a page with XML tags.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>By placing individual text boxes over individual paragraphs on the page, Finereader would output the OCRed text in a form that was sectionally pre-divided within the plain-text-viewer. By easily distinguishing the divisions with physical space, it allowed me to rapidly go through and paste repetitive structural elements. Additionally, the image of the page (that would automatically relocate to the plain text&amp;rsquo;s location when I selected it) that was always visible aided me in determining how exactly to structure the divisions to both best maintain the paper&amp;rsquo;s original appearance and take advantage of the power of XML coding to analyze it. I then used Oxygen to functionally check and edit the code. Combined, I found that these factors greatly reduced the amount of time it took me to structurally code the text.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The World's Worst Job</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scrolling through the financial tables listed on January 9th, I came across a chart detailing ivory deliveries to London. In the midst of reflecting on what 39 tons of elephant tusks would look like, I noticed an odd source of ivory mentioned in the chart: &amp;ldquo;Sea Horse Teeth.&amp;rdquo; This piqued my curiosity, as I had no idea that sea horses were a source of ivory. I immediately began to scheme&amp;ndash;I could open the first sustainable sea horse ivory farm. But in the midst of this, a problem arose. How does one extract sea horse teeth? Tweezers and a magnifying glass? That sounds like a painstakingly miserable job. Also the chart mentioned that 10 cwt. 1 qrs. 14 lb. (about 144 pounds) of sea horse teeth were delivered! How long would extracting that many teeth take? It might be a venture perfectly suited for the British Colonial project, but I realized I had much less capital to work with (also less forced native labor). It dawned on me that there is no earthly way that this chart is talking about the same sea horse that I am familiar with. A google search revealed I was not the first person to be puzzled about the true source of this ivory. &lt;a href="http://oldblockwriter.blogspot.com/2013/01/the-mystery-of-seahorse-teeth.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">This link&lt;/a> describes a writer&amp;rsquo;s journey though old trade documents to discover what animal exactly is being referred to after encountering a similar reference to sea horse teeth, before finally realizing that sea horses don&amp;rsquo;t even have teeth!&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure id="figure-misinformed-propaganda">
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="seahorsedentist.jpg" srcset="
/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/seahorsedentist_hu564ab95309309d2f87747724bcb66be7_971795_8fb86bd290eb1ede2cf00094d2a62e98.webp 400w,
/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/seahorsedentist_hu564ab95309309d2f87747724bcb66be7_971795_d3f7d521a6763fcf347312bb00de9258.webp 760w,
/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/seahorsedentist_hu564ab95309309d2f87747724bcb66be7_971795_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-21-crawford-worldsworstjob/seahorsedentist_hu564ab95309309d2f87747724bcb66be7_971795_8fb86bd290eb1ede2cf00094d2a62e98.webp"
width="644"
height="760"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;figcaption>
Misinformed Propaganda
&lt;/figcaption>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>His conclusion was that it depended on the source of the shipment. If from the polar areas, it would be walrus, but if from Africa, it would be referring to hippopotamus teeth. I admit, in this context hippopotamus teeth makes a lot more sense. The word hippopotamus originally comes from Greek, and translates to &amp;ldquo;river horse,&amp;rdquo; while the genus of the seahorse, hippocampus, comes from the Greek words for horse and sea monster. It would seem perhaps that these animals were named a bit backwards. I haven&amp;rsquo;t been able to find official data on seahorse attack fatalities, but what I have read of hippopotamus&amp;rsquo; make them seem far more monstrous, with one article quoting a statistic provided by the Bill &amp;amp; Melinda Gates foundation that the animal causes upwards of 500 fatalities a year. This chart also provides a snapshot of the global ivory trade before it was realized how much environmental damage was actually being done. See &lt;a href="http://nationalgeographic.org/media/history-ivory-trade/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">this link&lt;/a> for a short documentary on the subject. So while my hopes for a sustainable ivory business might be dashed, I suppose the sea horses can rest easy for now.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>