<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>prison | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/prison/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/prison/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>prison</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>prison</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/prison/</link></image><item><title>Prison Scurvy</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-27-pazos/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-27-pazos/</guid><description>&lt;p>In Egypt, 30 cases of scurvy occurred in prisons. This interested me because nowadays, scurvy does not happen in prison even though some prisons don&amp;rsquo;t serve the most nutritious of foods. This made me wonder how bad the food must have been in the prisons in terms of nutrition, where the prisoners were being fed but got so little nutrition that they developed scurvy. From the sources I looked into, Egypt had a very developed prison system, however it was mainly focused on punishment rather than rehabilitation. This makes me think that the prisoners that developed scurvy most likely lost some sort of food privileges, such as fresh vegetables or other sources of Vitamin C. By the 1900&amp;rsquo;s, the causes and prevention of scurvy were well known, so no one actually died from getting it, and the worst of the cases were mild. Overall, from my research, prisons in Egypt were far from the worst that the world had, and the prisoners had medical care and some rights and were not left to die.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Maxim Gorki</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-05-chacon-gorki/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-05-05-chacon-gorki/</guid><description>&lt;p>Something that has caught my eye while reading these articles from March 1905 to April 1905 is that on the first issue on the third day, there is a small article about a man by the name of Maxim Gorki.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It says he is to be prosecuted because charges have been given to him that he drafted proclamations aiming to overthrow the existing state of the Empire. It also says his health has broken down and that he is liable to three years of detention in a fortress. It also then gives the day of the trial. Gorki is said to be in a place called Riga and is under surveillance. I find this curious because I would like to know more information on this matter. I would also like to know how the trial ended up. I also find it curious because it is such a small article about this man&amp;rsquo;s prosecution. I would think it would be longer. I would also like to know about the place, Riga, that he is in and if he is such a dangerous criminal that he has to be under surveillance.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>