<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>bubonic Plague | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/bubonic-plague/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/bubonic-plague/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>bubonic Plague</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>bubonic Plague</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/bubonic-plague/</link></image><item><title>Bubonic Plague's Continuation Into the 20th Century</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/</guid><description>&lt;p>While encoding my 1906-10-17 issue of the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>, I was enthralled by mention of the bubonic plague in the “Local and General” section. The bubonic plague is a bacterial infection commonly carried by fleas and rats that causes fever, swollen lymph nodes, and even gangrene in the extremities, hence its nickname the &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2090123213001380" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Black death&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>. I was familiar with this plague’s epidemic in Western Europe during the 14th century, but I had not realized that the plague continued to infect humans. Upon further research, I learned that there was &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0033350607000145" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a second epidemic of the bubonic plague in India&lt;/a> throughout the 19th and 20th centuries for about five decades. Cases of bubonic plague persist around the world &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/cid/article/49/5/736/308284" target="_blank" rel="noopener">still even to this day&lt;/a>, which I found particularly intriguing; it completely dumbfounded my previous notions that the plague no longer existed. Specifically in the context of Egypt in the early 20th century, I learned from &lt;a href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/17-analysis-migdalski/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">past student blog posts&lt;/a> that the plague was most prevalent in 1904, followed by an immediate, drastic decrease in 1905. In fact, there was a bulletin posted in October of 1905 that read &lt;a href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-eugenio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;NO MORE PLAGUE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> Within just two years, the total cases dropped to zero, which I found compelling considering the plague’s reputation of spreading viscously. My issue’s report of the plague’s reappearance further complicates the issue of the bubonic plague in early 20th century Egypt; what allowed the plague to dwindle down and reappear? What specific conditions fostered an epidemic in India but not in Egypt when they were dealing with the same disease? These are questions that microhistorical data in the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> can help answer. I also think it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the afflicted person in this bulletin was a waiter, meaning he had ample opportunity to transmit the disease to countless other people. A later issue in the same month of that year revealed that there had been 500 cases from January to October in 1906, which is a stark increase from the supposedly zero cases in 1905; this all leads me to conclude that this case of plague was not rare for the time, and that the plague reappeared with a vigor. I wonder, too, if there was any significance to the newspaper mentioning that he was Greek; was this their way of racializing the disease? Upon looking futher into the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>, I discovered a trend in reporting individual cases of the bubonic plague with little to no detail in the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section. In issues &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/1905-page-images-1/1905-01-13-p3.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">like this one&lt;/a>, the bulletins were only concerned with sharing the numbers of cases and the deaths. (In this issue, the &amp;ldquo;Bubonic Plague&amp;rdquo; bulletin is in the third column.) Rarely did they report the occupation or ethnicity of someone afflicted, which makes this particular bulletin all the more interesting and worthy of research.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Bubonic Plague</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Mar 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/</guid><description>&lt;p>#The Bubonic Plague has Arrived
##Striking Now in Egypt
Spread by Rats and Fleas
The Bubonic Plague has spread from many areas of SouthEast Asia, namely India, and has reached Egypt. The disease has affected many people and places, including Alexandria.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="The Plague Strikes" srcset="
/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_0bed7ee50ffb53298a2d8c74ff56d894.webp 400w,
/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_09e4d33a5bb207fce8205e7df7ae88b2.webp 760w,
/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_0bed7ee50ffb53298a2d8c74ff56d894.webp"
width="760"
height="491"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Many people have come down with the disease, and many have been admitted to hospitals. Deaths have also been
associated with this deadly disease. The disease has turned into an epidemic since it once again arose from the depths of ancient times. According to &lt;a href="http://jmvh.org/article/the-history-of-plague-part-1-the-three-great-pandemics/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">JMVH&lt;/a>, this new plague, still spread from rats and rat fleas, has taken over all parts of the world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Unfortunately, it has reached Egypt and Alexandria and has no signs of stopping anytime soon. Death rates are high for the disease, and in some cities without hospitals many people are at risk. The &lt;a href="https://www.cdc.gov/plague/history/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">CDC&lt;/a> has reported that people should stay away from many of the rats infecting cities, because the cause of the disease is unknown as of yet. Many people die each day as reported in the newspapers, and more are being committed into hospitals at the same time. Many hope that the death rates of the plague decrease over time, but for many people whose family members have already been infected have little hope for the future. Some talk about vaccines and ways to stop the disease, but we have not received any of it yet because people are still dying. Many people in the areas affected by the plague cannot afford to find help, so in some cases, they are left to die on the streets.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Death on the Street" srcset="
/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_0bed7ee50ffb53298a2d8c74ff56d894.webp 400w,
/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_09e4d33a5bb207fce8205e7df7ae88b2.webp 760w,
/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-03-05-anderson-bubonicplague/AndersonBubonicPlague2_hu7bd6adf8be44111d7e76815a2821e2be_1482878_0bed7ee50ffb53298a2d8c74ff56d894.webp"
width="760"
height="491"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bubonic Plague In Egypt</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/</guid><description>&lt;p>According to the Egyptian Gazette, August 28, 1905, the Bubonic plague has reported at least thirteen cases of individuals that had contracted this disease.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Interest in this snippet of information, housed within the Gazette (see figure below), stems from the fact that the Bubonic Plague (a.k.a. The Black Death), was not confined to Medieval Europe (as many readers would suspect). In fact, the Bubonic plague has existed for thousands of years, the first known case being recorded in China dating back to 224 B.C.E..&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The most significant outbreak, and most noticeable, occurred in Europe in the mid-fourteenth century over a five year period (1347 to 1352). During this time period, sources indicate that at least 25 million people died, about one-third of the continent’s population (these numbers are disputed). The often disputed claims as to the cause of such a disease was further investigated in 2010 and 2011, when researchers analyzed DNA from some of its European victims. The consensus to date is that the pathogen responsible was the Yersinia pestis bacterium, which most likely caused several different forms of the plague.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="image name"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-11-06-cyr-bubonic-plague/BlackPlague.gif"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Seeing an outbreak within the borders of Egypt, with so few deaths was incredible, which warrants further understanding of this disease, how it was spread and who it affected. The Gazette’s article (above) mentions that approximately 13 cases were under treatment during the middle of August and beginning of September, 1905. With the plague’s notorious reputation, the Gazette’s allocated space to this pandemic is sapient, especially due to the many cattle deaths in the area within that same time period (the figure to the right indicates the area affected by the Bubonic Plague).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>With modern populations shifted to cities in modern day, an unidentifiable plague in one of these areas would prove to be even more catastrophic than ever before.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="for-further-study">For further study:&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Yersinia Pestis.
&lt;a href="https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951374/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.ncbi.nlm.nih.gov/pmc/articles/PMC2951374/&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>A Draft genome of Yersinia pestis from victims of the Black Death.
&lt;a href="https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v478/n7370/full/nature10549.html" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.nature.com/nature/journal/v478/n7370/full/nature10549.html&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Plague in 18th Century Egypt.
&lt;a href="https://contagions.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/plague-in-18th-century-egypt/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://contagions.wordpress.com/2010/05/26/plague-in-18th-century-egypt/&lt;/a>&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>