<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>McKenna Oakley | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mckennaoakley/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mckennaoakley/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>McKenna Oakley</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mckennaoakley/avatar_hu5da1a3994fe0a0b775b79de918c189e0_74056_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>McKenna Oakley</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/mckennaoakley/</link></image><item><title>How can microhistorical digital research methods apply to questions concerning qualitative data</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction">Introduction&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Our group is filled with many different questions with very few similarities between them all, however, after looking through what we were each using as a question and how we were researching we came to the conclusion that our group would best be summarized as one based around qualitative research. The question we decided to base our research on is how qualitative questions lead to the development of research techniques with xml and regular expression. The way to answer this question took us a long time to figure out due to how large of a question this is, we ended up having to collaborate and brainstorm many different ideas before coming up with a simple and effective solution. The solution we came up with to achieve this task was to create a general Xpath query that we could use in each of our individual projects and compare and contrast the data and information we got with this query. We all created visualizations based off of this Xpath query to make this goal more achievable. The question itself and the methodology used to solve were very useful for each of our individual projects, especially as many of our personal questions are complicated and difficult to answer. With this group project question we can work on our own projects as a side effect of the group project question we are answering. In summary, we are a qualitative data group who are trying to answer how qualitative questions lead to the development of research techniques with xml and regular expression.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="finding-a-query">Finding a Query&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>As our group had many different topics, finding a common query seemed like a rather daunting task. Tying religion to military ranks to mummies, etc. looked to be somewhat impossible, especially considering how each individual project was specific in its own unique way. Thus, our query ended up being broad to fit the various objectives we had, which ended up being tied to our research methods (qualitative research). The query ended up being how many times a certain word that related to our project showed up across the entire Egyptian Gazette digital catalog, in any feature. We had mentions of the words: “Commander”, “Turks”, “Migration”, “Yours truly”, and so on and so forth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The expression we ended up using was //div[matches(.,&amp;lsquo;x&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;)]/@feature, with “x” being the word we searched for. We put this into the XPath 2.0 search bar in the Oxygen Editor and queried the contents of the whole newspaper with our individual terms. Once the whole contents were queried, we copied over the results into a plain text editor, where we would edit it to be usable in an Excel spreadsheet. From there, we would copy it into Tableau, the application that visualizes the results.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The way the query worked shows how similar our data collection methods are. While the query itself is incredibly broad, it is a good representation of what we will do in our individual analysis projects. Specific searches would not work; thus, this method is likely the lowest common denominator that we have as a group.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="creating-visualizations">Creating Visualizations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>With our XPath query, we were searching for a few simple results in common for otherwise uncommon topics of study. Our query yielded the feature, date, and page number of every division that contained a keyword of our respective independent research efforts. With this data we sought to generate a set of visualizations that used the same type of data in roughly the same style and theme, to be easily compared to one another for possible similarities and discrepancies in the patterns of each, which could indicate a connection between the different topics.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>We chose to use the date, feature count, page number, and feature for our visualizations. We formatted them in roughly the same manner, with a basic scatterplot styling. We placed the date variable along the x-axis and plotted the page number variable along the y-axis. The feature count data points are placed at each of their respective dates and page numbers, and then color coded each data point with its corresponding feature name.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This method of visualization provides for a simplistic, understandable representation of our data. The matching formats and color coding allow for an easy way to compare our seemingly unrelated data just from glancing at each of the charts. Weaknesses of this visualization are that you cannot gather much just from these charts, only use them to infer about events that may have caused them to have patterns that coincide at the same time, leading to further investigation and research. While that is a glaring weakness, there is not much else to start out from researching, as the topics in question do not have much in common, so we must find similarities and differences before any reasoning can be found.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="comparing-and-contrasting-our-visualizations">Comparing and Contrasting Our Visualizations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once we completed our visualizations, we could embark on the analysis of our results. Since we each had such vast individual research topics, we were interested in comparing variables like page number, amount of data, the features that appeared most often, and the overall function our data would serve. Some proved to be more feasible than others:&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="1-page-number">1. Page Number&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Wyatt&amp;amp;rsquo;s Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Wyatt_hu41861e00a4548436359cf9b514d2d5c0_68346_409533dc1f57040db6fd0fd70d34817a.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Wyatt_hu41861e00a4548436359cf9b514d2d5c0_68346_78737d6337e9dfc7a1048181e6a11e06.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Wyatt_hu41861e00a4548436359cf9b514d2d5c0_68346_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Wyatt_hu41861e00a4548436359cf9b514d2d5c0_68346_409533dc1f57040db6fd0fd70d34817a.webp"
width="760"
height="705"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Miriam&amp;amp;rsquo;s Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Miriam_hued41b64ebde6dc0ed991b01e7a5ec023_71035_07e114c15747b00c251d191cdfd10a01.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Miriam_hued41b64ebde6dc0ed991b01e7a5ec023_71035_6bdfb833967e391ecdb4d128710b876c.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Miriam_hued41b64ebde6dc0ed991b01e7a5ec023_71035_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Miriam_hued41b64ebde6dc0ed991b01e7a5ec023_71035_07e114c15747b00c251d191cdfd10a01.webp"
width="760"
height="310"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Harrison&amp;amp;rsquo;s Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Harrison_hu77d34e555ff2a7e53c3325820632cb87_65520_b903f6c061a9a1e8ff1d792764f144a6.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Harrison_hu77d34e555ff2a7e53c3325820632cb87_65520_879d68f771cbf65ca7a0f04173402dfb.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Harrison_hu77d34e555ff2a7e53c3325820632cb87_65520_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Harrison_hu77d34e555ff2a7e53c3325820632cb87_65520_b903f6c061a9a1e8ff1d792764f144a6.webp"
width="760"
height="721"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
As we completed our individual research, we realized that there is more variance than we originally expected. While our visualizations are fundamentally the same, they each present data differently. Since we all align under the scope of qualitative research, we expected most results to appear on page three of The Egyptian Gazette. However, our visualizations show that research relating to individuals (for example: &amp;ldquo;Commander&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Migration&amp;rdquo;) appears to spread across more pages than visualizations based on specific topics (for example: &amp;ldquo;Religion&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Mummy&amp;rdquo;).&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="2-features">2. Features&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Rainey&amp;amp;rsquo;s Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Rainey_huc7a5753d51b08e352dd19ff19df42f62_101141_5bec67ec78fedd8a322ff46958e30a61.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Rainey_huc7a5753d51b08e352dd19ff19df42f62_101141_9b2ffa8e55eeacd5d13bd1da5d8ad5df.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Rainey_huc7a5753d51b08e352dd19ff19df42f62_101141_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Rainey_huc7a5753d51b08e352dd19ff19df42f62_101141_5bec67ec78fedd8a322ff46958e30a61.webp"
width="760"
height="270"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="McKenna&amp;amp;rsquo;s Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_4479d45fbcaecfe9c592356015d3c1c1.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_56aee731844f6524e93be2a37543b1de.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_4479d45fbcaecfe9c592356015d3c1c1.webp"
width="760"
height="705"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
While comparing the visualizations, we also looked at the features where our data most appeared. It is difficult to identify exact results since the paper includes incomplete sections that do not have feature titles. This allows for easier navigation but does not show a complete picture. The features vary depending on the intentions of the research. The &amp;ldquo;yours truly&amp;rdquo; query appeared most in the Letters feature since it was specific to the Letter to the Editor section of the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>. We ran the Xpath query to limit the search results to useful data rather than to identify the most common feature. This allowed for better quantitative data use during the research process. Contrastly, qualitative research attempts to discover which features discussed the topic. For example, the &amp;ldquo;Mummy&amp;rdquo; Xpath query revealed the most used features were Local and Egyptological. This led to more research questions and was used to understand the importance of mummies to the readers of the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;h3 id="3-data-spikes">3. Data Spikes&lt;/h3>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Ben&amp;amp;rsquo;s Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Ben_huceb8b2b0cda0d3c2b273aef30bdbe0d6_44905_d21e86d962a3bd7ed71361aef6ce3763.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Ben_huceb8b2b0cda0d3c2b273aef30bdbe0d6_44905_3f13475cdde273598025948a14a74812.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Ben_huceb8b2b0cda0d3c2b273aef30bdbe0d6_44905_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-qualitative-group/Ben_huceb8b2b0cda0d3c2b273aef30bdbe0d6_44905_d21e86d962a3bd7ed71361aef6ce3763.webp"
width="760"
height="721"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
It was alluring to see when specific results spiked and dipped in results. However, when we attempted to draw links between rises and falls between visualizations, the results were inconclusive. In the Fall of 2006, the &amp;ldquo;religion&amp;rdquo; visualization displayed an uptick in results. We attempted to research the reason and compare it to the uptick of results for the &amp;ldquo;Turks&amp;rdquo; visualization: to no avail. Since the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> files are incomplete, it is challenging to know if the spike is due to complete access to data or the paper&amp;rsquo;s coverage of the topic at the time.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="overall-strengths--weaknesses-in-microhistorical-qualitative-research">Overall Strengths &amp;amp; Weaknesses In Microhistorical Qualitative Research&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Ultimately, the digital research methods we used with the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> as our microhistorical source were complex and nuanced per each person&amp;rsquo;s research question; due to these complexities and nuances, various strengths and weaknesses arose during the employment of our chosen methods. A chief strength of our chosen XPath query and visualization format was their ability to encapsulate the significance of our search terms. The sheer quantity of results that our queries yielded provided us with adequate perceptions of how significant our chosen research topics were within the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em>, which is a useful starting point for the research process. Our chosen query and visualization also demonstrate the distribution of our search terms over multiple years of &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> issues. The ability to ascertain any trends in the mentions of our search terms, such as if the term has a higher proportional frequency in certain months, is vital for the qualitative research we each embarked on. Our understanding of potential trends allowed for further research and analysis since we could consult secondary sources or more XPath query results to help explain these trends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Some weaknesses arose, though, from the confining nature of our chosen XPath query. Our query limited our results to only yield from &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> items labeled as features. Although this provided each of us with a smaller, much more manageable amount of data than a raw word count, it significantly limited the amount and types of trends we could analyze. Also, a weakness arises from the rather rudimental level of our chosen visualizations. Although these visualizations provided sufficient starting points for the research process, they did not yield enough data alone to be able to approach each of our complex qualitative research questions. This weakness, though, is merely reflective of the holistic qualitative research process. Qualitative research&amp;rsquo;s reliance on data beyond easily quantifiable characteristics meant we had to get creative to come up with numerical data for each of our projects. Many of us had to try multiple search terms that were relevant to our research topics before we even acquired enough data to transfer to a visualization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ultimately, we feel that our chosen XPath query and visualization format effectively initiated our research processes and created a compelling concept to discuss as a group. The query and visualization format may not have been enough to answer our research questions by themselves, but they were helpful when accompanied by further research. We recommend utilizing similar digital methods to other qualitative researchers; however, we suggest limiting the XPath queries to multiple types of items within the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> rather than just features to see if another query yields a more desirable amount of results. Overall, these digital methods are imperfect, but in their imperfections, they reflect the unique limits and challenges of microhistorical research.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Digital Microhistory as a whole serves as an experimentational launching board between the realms of quantitative and qualitative analysis, and by nature our project was able to develop into an apt reflection of that reality. Within our project’s inquiry, we were faced with challenges beyond the scope of the dichotomy of using computational methodology to encompass qualitative data, specifically in that each specific personal topic was vastly different from the other. In the pursuit of trying to understand how to bridge these gaps, we developed a slightly broadened X-Path query, //div[matches(.,&amp;lsquo;x&amp;rsquo;, &amp;lsquo;i&amp;rsquo;)]/@feature, in order to encompass a similar objective within a common research method. It was through this we came to realize that within the confines of qualitative data, a good launching pad is looking at numerical counts of usage of “trigger words” along with location of said usage, and moreover supplies a unifying factor between distinct topics of qualitative research. In looking to display our data we opted for a scatterplot styling as it most aptly reflected the particular factors returned from our query: feature, date, feature count, and page number of every division that contained a keyword of our respective research efforts. This visualization was an easily understandable representation of our findings, and allowed for effectiveness in comparing various results across the independent research efforts. These differences highlighted certain vantage and null points for each individual project, and supplemented our notions as to where to continue looking for more specific information on our individual topics. In reflection, we realized that the query was able to encapsulate the significance of key terms while also serving as a helpful catalyst into more specialized research; however, while supplying us with a more workable set of data it limits the amount/type of trends we could analyze, and so you would need more queries in order to substantially supplement one’s research. Overall, the most profound lesson learned was the amount of work and research that could still be done in regards to computational research methods concerning qualitative data, and that it is necessary to go through multiple rounds of trial and error and experimentation in order to find more defined yet transferable methods of querying for qualitative data. Furthermore, it may be concluded that in the vast diversity within qualitative data that a “one-size-fits-all query” simply can not be overarchingly specific and yield consistent, detailed, and specialized results for each pursued topic. Ultimately, this project reflected the intricacies encompassed in the microhistorical digital research methodology in order to relate the surface level disconnect between qualitative information and computational analysis.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is the Cultural Significance of Mummies in Early 20th Century Egypt?</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-oakley/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-oakley/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction--research-question">Introduction &amp;amp; Research Question&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Before my learning in this course, the only Egyptological concept I was somewhat familiar with was that of the mummy. Mummies are the remains of humans or animals that have been preserved through specific ceremonial practices, such as removing internal organs and wrapping their bodies with bandages. Growing up in modern Western culture, I was exposed to mummies in museums, history textbooks, and countless movies, TV shows, and books. I never learned about them in-depth, though. Furthermore, they seemed to be exploited for their &amp;ldquo;creepy&amp;rdquo; factor rather than their cultural significance. Time and time again, I witnessed mummies portrayed as monsters instead of valuable cultural artifacts.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Already faintly accustomed to this unfairness in the representation of Egyptian tradition, I was especially shocked when I realized that after encoding several issues of the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>, I had not read a single mention of mummies. Based on the stereotypical portrayals of Egyptian culture in Western media, I expected plentiful discussions on mummies in the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em>. This gap between stereotypical expectations and reality intrigued me; I instantly wanted to know more about mummies and their actual cultural significance beyond what American Hollywood films had led me to believe. With all this in mind, I decided to explore &amp;ldquo;What was the cultural significance of mummies in the early 20th century?&amp;rdquo; as my research question. I limited the scope of my findings to the early 20th century to better utilize our course&amp;rsquo;s repository of &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> records.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="queries--visualizations">Queries &amp;amp; Visualizations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I began my research with the following X-Path query:
&lt;code>//div[matches(.,'mummy', 'i')]/@feature&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I started with this relatively broad query to find which features had the most frequent mentions of the word &amp;ldquo;mummy,&amp;rdquo; or at least to find some sort of other noticeable trend in the word use that could help me narrow my research scope in further queries. Based on the results from this query, I created the following data visualization.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="1st Query Visualization" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_4479d45fbcaecfe9c592356015d3c1c1.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_56aee731844f6524e93be2a37543b1de.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-1_hu0c4b9cde2d41f983e8b0381761303f67_83846_4479d45fbcaecfe9c592356015d3c1c1.webp"
width="760"
height="705"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>As is evident in the graph, the query only yielded eleven issues with features that mentioned the word &amp;ldquo;mummy.&amp;rdquo; Based on this number, I inferred that many uses of the word probably occurred in segments of the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> that were not labeled as features. Whether this was due to human entry error in our course repository or not, I could tell that this query alone was not fruitful enough to serve as the sole basis for my research. A helpful conclusion I could draw from the results of this query, though, was that mentions of &amp;ldquo;mummy&amp;rdquo; occurred at a proportionally higher rate amongst the results on page three of the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> issues. This finding was not what I initially had in mind when I used a query focused on features, but I was grateful to have a starting point for the next query. I refined my second query to only search for word mentions on the third page of &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> issues to see whether this would bring me more results, specifically because this query was not limited to segments labeled as features. My goal was for this next set of results to provide me with a richer variety of information that could help me ultimately answer my research question.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My second, more niche query ended up looking like this:
&lt;code>//div[@type=&amp;quot;page&amp;quot;][@n=&amp;quot;3&amp;quot;]//div[matches(.,'mummy', 'i')]&lt;/code>&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Much to my delight, this query yielded thirty-seven articles that mentioned my search term. I created the bar graph below to help me visualize this data and spot any trends.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="2nd Query Visualization Part 1" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-1_hu180c19108fe4421fe02c28dc9a256211_209464_deb5606349cfd060025b96c3d2c24f47.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-1_hu180c19108fe4421fe02c28dc9a256211_209464_e5738b446813d34ab23ca1ba0b2d6b25.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-1_hu180c19108fe4421fe02c28dc9a256211_209464_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-1_hu180c19108fe4421fe02c28dc9a256211_209464_deb5606349cfd060025b96c3d2c24f47.webp"
width="760"
height="721"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="2nd Query Visualization Part 2" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-2_hu331036acafd3c0320ccd14d349c0dc9b_82218_4d7cdc6927def6dcf5c774f8ebc5bc27.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-2_hu331036acafd3c0320ccd14d349c0dc9b_82218_c51b1423c9c61483aa99747790e8368b.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-2_hu331036acafd3c0320ccd14d349c0dc9b_82218_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-oakley/Story-2-2_hu331036acafd3c0320ccd14d349c0dc9b_82218_4d7cdc6927def6dcf5c774f8ebc5bc27.webp"
width="760"
height="246"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is worth noting that the visualized data above only portrays a proportion of total mentions of my search term because I confined the query to a specific page number rather than a raw word count. This proportional data, though, was immensely helpful in narrowing down the number of articles I could read that discussed mummies rather than just any &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> item that happened to use the word &amp;ldquo;mummy.&amp;rdquo; Thirty-seven articles were substantial enough to provide me with further insight into the cultural significance of mummies in Egypt at the newspaper&amp;rsquo;s time while still being a manageable amount of data. Overall, I was pleased with the results of my second XPath query and felt that it provided sufficient material to move from the exploratory to the analytical phase of my project.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began my analysis by ascertaining trends in the visualized data above. I found that &amp;ldquo;mummy&amp;rdquo; was used the most in 1905 with sixteen mentions, followed by seven in 1906, then a spike to twelve in 1907, and ultimately only two in 1908. Although this data would suggest a drastic decrease in interest in mummy-related topics, I could not draw any significant conclusions from the lack of mentions in 1908 due to the fact that our course repository does not have many issues from that year in general.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Furthermore, I tried to focus on the months of the word mentions to see if there were any times of the year when mentions were most frequent. However, I was unsuccessful in determining any rhyme or reason to the word mentions. None of the months or overall seasons experienced a higher rate of mentions than others. Ultimately, the only trend I could conclude from my visualized data was the lack thereof; from an analytical standpoint, the use of the word &amp;ldquo;mummy&amp;rdquo; seemed random and did not follow any visible patterns.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="data-interpretation--supplementary-research">Data Interpretation &amp;amp; Supplementary Research&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Once I read the articles yielded by my second XPath query in my next phase of analysis, I quickly noticed that at this point in Egyptian history, mummies were more of a cultural spectacle for other countries than a sacred practice for native Egyptians to prepare for the afterlife, as they were in ancient times. Most of the articles discussed mummies in relation to museum exhibits or the projects of American Egyptologists. For instance, in the article &amp;ldquo;The Pharaoh of the Exodus,&amp;rdquo; from the 1905-12-26 &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> issue, it was recorded that &amp;ldquo;A discovery of the utmost importance has just been made by the well-known American Egyptologist, Mr. Theodore M. Davis, who has discovered in the valley of the Tombs of the Kings, the tomb of Mer-en Ptah, a pharaoh of the 19th dynasty &amp;hellip; This pharaoh, who is also known as Meneptah, is thought by many to have been the pharaoh of the Exodus. His mummy was found in the tomb of Amenhotep II at Thebes.&amp;rdquo; I found this evidence of excavation work, and other articles like it, to be the most compelling because they demonstrated that the fascination with mummies during this time primarily came from foreigners rather than native Egyptians. Here is where I began to think that perhaps the mummy was more important to curious outsiders than the Egyptians themselves.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My interpretive conclusion grew as I read the remaining articles from my query. Many of them discussed European collectors of mummies, and one article entitled &amp;ldquo;Egyptian Mummies, No Fabrication&amp;rdquo; from the 1907-10-03 &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> issue even divulged the easy accessibility of mummies: &amp;ldquo;Besides, the supply of mummies is practically inexhaustible and the price of an ordinary one is so low that a manufacturer in Paris could not box his mummy and send it to Cairo to be sold for the price that the genuine article can be bought at there, with its painted case and the certificate of the Cairo museum as to its genuineness.&amp;rdquo; Not only does the wide circulation and affordability of mummies in this newspaper excerpt point to their exploitation and spectacle nature, but the flippant tone of the writer suggests that mummies were not respected as culturally significant. The writer treated mummies as decorative commodities rather than artifacts of a practice that was sacred to ancient Egypt. Most of the articles fell under these larger categories of museums, exhibits, foreigners&amp;rsquo; excavations, or foreigners&amp;rsquo; mummy collections. The rest of the articles were random and largely insignificant, or sometimes redundant, such as the multiple articles referring to a sketch called &amp;ldquo;The Mummy and the Mummer,&amp;rdquo; written and performed by an Englishman. Even these seemingly unimportant articles further exemplify the fascination with and the spectacle nature of mummies in non-Egyptian cultures.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Once I had my preliminary conclusions formed from my research in the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em>, I consulted secondary sources to see if they would substantiate or refute my findings. After sifting through many academic articles, I found a consensus with my notion that mummies were largely valued in the early twentieth century purely as a cultural spectacle and a means to exploit and objectify Egyptian culture, primarily by Europeans and Americans. In the article &lt;a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/journals/science-in-context/article/between-spectacle-and-science-margaret-murray-and-the-tomb-of-the-two-brothers/BD9BF4396C3C3AEE6CD594BAB2E5BA73" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Between Spectacle and Science: Margaret Murray and the Tomb of the Two Brothers&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>, it even discusses the popularity of mummy unwrappings in England at the early twentieth century. The article describes these public unwrappings as &amp;ldquo;public spectacles which displayed and objectified exotic artifacts&amp;rdquo; (Sheppard). Although the goals of some mummy unwrappings were rooted in scientific investigation, the vast majority of unwrappings served as entertainment, demonstrating a regard for mummies as culturally insignificant. In the article &lt;a href="https://muse.jhu.edu/article/184522" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Unswathing the Mummy: Body, Knowledge, and Writing in Gautier’s Le Roman de la momie&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>, I learned that this tradition of unwrapping mummies for public spectacle had spread throughout Europe, specifically in France. Curious as to when this trend in desecrating mummies for public interest began, I found an article called &lt;a href="https://www.cambridge.org/core/books/abs/popular-exhibitions-science-and-showmanship-18401910/unwrapping-the-past-egyptian-mummies-on-show/F68462C54FA7D5FAC336412E3AB36F9E" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Unwrapping the Past: Egyptian Mummies on Show&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> that detailed an &amp;ldquo;incredible rise [in the 1820s] in the acquisition of Egyptian mummies for souvenirs and as artefacts for collection and display. [Mummies were] treated more as commodities and historical specimens than as human remains, they were displayed, unwrapped, cut open and divested of their funerary goods, all in the name of knowledge&amp;rdquo; (Rogers). This source effectively traces the sparked interest in mummies and their degradation at the hands of non-Egyptian collectors, historians, and scientists to the early 1800s. It became apparent to me that the treatment of mummies as insignificant objects within and beyond the borders of Egypt far predated the issues of the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> that we examine in this course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="conclusion">Conclusion&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>My ultimate conclusion from my research in both the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> and outside academic sources is that mummies in the early twentieth-century were culturally insignificant, or at least were treated as such. Mummies seemed to derive their value as spectacles and commodities rather than artifacts that still served a critical purpose to their native culture.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, a weakness of my digital research methods in this project is that my microhistorical data only drew from a limited-perspective source: the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>. The &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> was written and published by the English forces occupying Egypt rather than native Egyptians. Ergo, coverage of mummies and related Egyptological topics came from a highly biased source. These topics most likely were not treated as culturally significant as they would have been if the newspaper were run by the native Egyptian population. Broadening my microhistorical data pool to include newspapers written by native Egyptians would have allowed me a more advanced analysis and overall stronger research conclusion. Given the microhistorical data I had to work with, my research conclusions more appropriately answer the question of how culturally significant mummies were to the English forces in early twentieth-century Egypt rather than their significance in general. This issue of bias in my microhistorical source is especially crucial since my research question deals with qualitative rather than quantitative data. I had to rely on the written content in the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> to answer my sociological research question rather than numbers from the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em>&amp;rsquo;s various tables and charts, which are not as directly impacted by the newspaper&amp;rsquo;s biases. Furthermore, the qualitative nature of my research question made finding numerical data to visualize for the project very difficult. I had to brainstorm which types of XPath queries would reveal data that would make sense or possibly lead to visible trends in a graph, which was complicated by my research question&amp;rsquo;s lack of adherence to any numerical concepts. If my research question was more inherently quantitative, I could have constructed more visually striking graphs that revealed more apparent trends in their data. Due to my research question&amp;rsquo;s reliance on qualitative over quantitative data, I found that much of the contextualization for the articles I yielded in my queries came from secondary sources rather than the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Although some weaknesses arose in my research from the limited scope of my microhistorical source and the lack of quantitative qualities in my research question, there were some strengths in the digital research methods I used. It may have been difficult to create data visualizations in my project; however, I think my ability to construct visual representations of the concepts I discussed made the data easier to follow for readers. Additionally, these visualizations helped me to form a fundamental understanding of my research topic before diving into my secondary research. Moreover, I think my ability to pull specific quotes from the broader microhistorical source for this project helped substantiate my research findings for myself and readers. Due to the qualitative nature of my research question, I could find quotes from the &lt;em>Gazette&lt;/em> that were relevant to my research and helped me reach a compelling conclusion with demonstrative ethos for readers. All in all, my research process was imperfect, but I think I found a sufficient answer to my initial research question through the microhistorical digital methods I learned in this course.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="works-cited">Works Cited&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Lyu, Claire. “Unswathing the Mummy: Body, Knowledge, and Writing in Gautieris Le Roman De La Momie.” Nineteenth Century French Studies, vol. 33, no. 3, 2005, pp. 308–319., &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1353/ncf.2005.0026" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://doi.org/10.1353/ncf.2005.0026&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Rogers, Beverley. “Unwrapping the Past: Egyptian Mummies on Show.” Popular Exhibitions, Science and Showmanship, 1840–1910, 2015, pp. 215–234., &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.4324/.9781315655123-19" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://doi.org/10.4324/.9781315655123-19&lt;/a>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Sheppard, Kathleen L. “Between Spectacle and Science: Margaret Murray and The Tomb of the Two Brothers.” Science in Context, vol. 25, no. 4, 2012, pp. 525–549., &lt;a href="https://doi.org/10.1017/s0269889712000221" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://doi.org/10.1017/s0269889712000221&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Bubonic Plague's Continuation Into the 20th Century</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/</guid><description>&lt;p>While encoding my 1906-10-17 issue of the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>, I was enthralled by mention of the bubonic plague in the “Local and General” section. The bubonic plague is a bacterial infection commonly carried by fleas and rats that causes fever, swollen lymph nodes, and even gangrene in the extremities, hence its nickname the &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/S2090123213001380" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;Black death&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a>. I was familiar with this plague’s epidemic in Western Europe during the 14th century, but I had not realized that the plague continued to infect humans. Upon further research, I learned that there was &lt;a href="https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/abs/pii/S0033350607000145" target="_blank" rel="noopener">a second epidemic of the bubonic plague in India&lt;/a> throughout the 19th and 20th centuries for about five decades. Cases of bubonic plague persist around the world &lt;a href="https://academic.oup.com/cid/article/49/5/736/308284" target="_blank" rel="noopener">still even to this day&lt;/a>, which I found particularly intriguing; it completely dumbfounded my previous notions that the plague no longer existed. Specifically in the context of Egypt in the early 20th century, I learned from &lt;a href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/17-analysis-migdalski/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">past student blog posts&lt;/a> that the plague was most prevalent in 1904, followed by an immediate, drastic decrease in 1905. In fact, there was a bulletin posted in October of 1905 that read &lt;a href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-eugenio/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">&amp;ldquo;NO MORE PLAGUE.&amp;rdquo;&lt;/a> Within just two years, the total cases dropped to zero, which I found compelling considering the plague’s reputation of spreading viscously.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Image label" srcset="
/post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_26f861be725f8c5c82c675772cbda8fd.webp 400w,
/post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_8414a6c43948a1f265daeb0ab33c2691.webp 760w,
/post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-20-oakley/featured_hub865316c5fbfc2c3432ce2477a9dce46_31237_26f861be725f8c5c82c675772cbda8fd.webp"
width="760"
height="229"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My issue’s report of the plague’s reappearance further complicates the issue of the bubonic plague in early 20th century Egypt; what allowed the plague to dwindle down and reappear? What specific conditions fostered an epidemic in India but not in Egypt when they were dealing with the same disease? These are questions that microhistorical data in the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> can help answer. I also think it&amp;rsquo;s important to note that the afflicted person in this bulletin was a waiter, meaning he had ample opportunity to transmit the disease to countless other people. A later issue in the same month of that year revealed that there had been 500 cases from January to October in 1906, which is a stark increase from the supposedly zero cases in 1905; this all leads me to conclude that this case of plague was not rare for the time, and that the plague reappeared with a vigor. I wonder, too, if there was any significance to the newspaper mentioning that he was Greek; was this their way of racializing the disease? Upon looking futher into the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em>, I discovered a trend in reporting individual cases of the bubonic plague with little to no detail in the &amp;ldquo;Local and General&amp;rdquo; section. In issues &lt;a href="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/dig-eg-gaz/page-images/master/1905-page-images-1/1905-01-13-p3.jpg" target="_blank" rel="noopener">like this one&lt;/a>, the bulletins were only concerned with sharing the numbers of cases and the deaths. (In this issue, the &amp;ldquo;Bubonic Plague&amp;rdquo; bulletin is in the third column.) Rarely did they report the occupation or ethnicity of someone afflicted, which makes this particular bulletin all the more interesting and worthy of research.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>