<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>chatham | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/chatham/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/chatham/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>chatham</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>chatham</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/chatham/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chatham Explosion</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This week of the &lt;strong&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/strong&gt; contained a consistent current event throughout the duration
of the week regarding the blowing up of an old naval vessel, &lt;em&gt;The Chatham&lt;/em&gt;.  Apparently being fairly important
news, as the vessel had wrecked in a major fresh water canal popular for the movement and
transportation of good, this week of the paper held a special section each day for the process
of the ship’s disposal.  The amount of dynamite that had been acquired to destroy the wreckage
was on pace to set a world record for the largest explosion of dynamite to date, weighing nearly
ninety two tons.  Of course, along with this massive amount of explosives came the necessity to
put to plan a series of precautions and emergency aids in case anything went wrong.  The
explosives were to be carried to the scene of the wreckage by train, and detonated through a
length of copper wire hooked up to a detonator.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;screenshot-name&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/wills-explosion-screenshot_hu6b520af5d7ba4c8f72737f0f8378198a_134703_7fc1e0a12981950a3cf2cbaaebc2896f.webp 400w,
               /post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/wills-explosion-screenshot_hu6b520af5d7ba4c8f72737f0f8378198a_134703_902bd705ecbae093053a4575ce6d1b26.webp 760w,
               /post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/wills-explosion-screenshot_hu6b520af5d7ba4c8f72737f0f8378198a_134703_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2016-10-13-chatham-explosion/wills-explosion-screenshot_hu6b520af5d7ba4c8f72737f0f8378198a_134703_7fc1e0a12981950a3cf2cbaaebc2896f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;648&#34;
               height=&#34;330&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The townspeople at this time were extremely
anxious for the explosion out of fear that some of their personal property may accidentally be
destroyed.  However, as the week continues on and the anticipation comes to rise, the people
near the explosion were shockingly disappointed in the effect of it.  Having built up a drastic
image in their mind, the world record shattering explosion was fairly disappointing to the
people, as they hardly even felt the shock being nineteen kilometers away from the site.  The
underwater explosion destroyed a decent amount of the naval vessel, while shooting tons of
sand, water, and other debris hundreds of feet in the air.  While the explosion was considered
a success, there was a slight repair process and one of the banks of the canal had been fairly
destroyed, and a number of railway lines needed repair.  However, officials told the paper
that transportation shouldn’t be delayed more than a few days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
