<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hayden Baker | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/haydenbaker/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/haydenbaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Hayden Baker</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/haydenbaker/avatar_hu5da1a3994fe0a0b775b79de918c189e0_74056_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Hayden Baker</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/haydenbaker/</link></image><item><title>Coal Resistance and Strikes</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-baker/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-baker/</guid><description>&lt;p>Black Monday 1987. The 2007-2008 Financial Crisis. Wall Street Crash of 1929. Financial
Crises go down in history as awful periods of time. Mass unemployment, smaller dinners,
starving times. Egypt fell into a recession in late 1906 - early 1907s, but how were different
markets of the Egypt economy affected by the crash? Can X-Path analysis tell us anything
about the origins and impact of the crash?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Using a series of cell-measure commands in X-path, I scanned the repository of
newspapers produced in Cairo in the 1900s to find the share price of three companies each in
different markets of the microeconomy. Record the share price each time they show up in the
issues and plot them to see the impact on each market specifically.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="label" srcset="
/post/2022-analysis-baker/image_hu63dc1ec0073730e377a0d05652239b73_36339_79afe27351272ebd0b3f5ddab6da2d72.webp 400w,
/post/2022-analysis-baker/image_hu63dc1ec0073730e377a0d05652239b73_36339_842cd90d6f6c4ea678ff64492e71fd0b.webp 760w,
/post/2022-analysis-baker/image_hu63dc1ec0073730e377a0d05652239b73_36339_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-baker/image_hu63dc1ec0073730e377a0d05652239b73_36339_79afe27351272ebd0b3f5ddab6da2d72.webp"
width="600"
height="371"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>After importing the data into google sheets, I was able to produce the above chart. We can see
the share prices dip in the 1906-1907 due to the crash. However, the crash seems to be equally
devastating to each market of the microeconomy in Cairo, and most surprisingly, the banks are
the most stable throughout the crash despite the nature of stock market crashes attacking the
banks first due to loan squeezes.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Yet, when you look up the stock market crash of 1907 in egypt. Most of the searched
results are about the New York stock crisis in 1907 and not about the crash in the
microeconomy of Egypt/Cairo. Country economies are like gears in a system, when one stops
or slows down, others are bound to be affected. The same effect can be seen in the stock
crashes in both Egypt and the United States.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>However, the data and specific results I retrieved from X-Path should be taken lightly due
to many errors and inconsistencies I found in the data.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coal Resistance and Strikes</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-15-baker/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-15-baker/</guid><description>&lt;p>On December 5th 1904, a German collier, a ship carrying coal, stopped at Cardiff. The captain and the head member of the ship were arrested shortly after. Why is the Egyptian government now prohibiting the transporting and usage of coal? Is this just Egypt preventing the use of coal? Coal is not useful anymore?&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Egyptian government officials watched their country become dirty, barren, and inhabitable as companies and industries became comfortable abusing coal to make energy. Coal was the primary source of energy for North African countries and cities across Europe for most of the century. Coal lit the homes of millions. However, after Thomas Edison proved that energy can be created via other more sustainable power sources, other countries wanted to implement similar mechanisms to help preserve their environment and prevent coal industries from gaining too much power.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The public had enough as well with the rise of better work environments and laws. Coal miners with the worst of the environments to work in became enthralled and wanted revenge against the corporate suits running their lives. Strikes across Europe and North Africa became a weekly occurrence. According to an article titled “Outsourcing: Energy and Empire in the Age of Coal” from the Cambridge University Press, “As in 1908 and earlier, the possibility of systematic transnational influence was always on the table. Even when investigations proved that strikes were not precipitated by “foreign agitators,” more subtle transregional mechanisms were at work. Consider a November 1910 strike of about one thousand coal heavers in the Port of Istanbul, who explicitly took advantage of the leverage afforded them by the situation in Ereģli and in England”. Coal had become the forbidden fruit for energy production, and Egypt decided to avoid the possibility of strikes and carnage in the city of Cairo despite neighboring countries such as Germany sticking with it.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Cameron Greco explores the prices changes and international feelings in her website entry posted back in April of 2017. &amp;ldquo;In January of 1905, coal prices were at 27.3 Shgs. per ton, and by the end of the recorded coal data, in September of 1906, the prices were at a steady level of 34 Shgs&amp;rdquo; states Cameron referring to the drastic increase in price of coal in Egypt. Coal was all the rage and all anyone could think about was producing more with little disregard for the environment. This pushed the workers past their limit causing strikes and prohibit of coal transportation in Egypt.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="label" srcset="
/post/2022-11-15-baker/featured_huea3868b59f21d6e7f5f827a6c7bfc672_3086598_cf1ea99cd0d09a66adcb7739b6a37fc6.webp 400w,
/post/2022-11-15-baker/featured_huea3868b59f21d6e7f5f827a6c7bfc672_3086598_021e9f34d91366bf945f323ae66b9524.webp 760w,
/post/2022-11-15-baker/featured_huea3868b59f21d6e7f5f827a6c7bfc672_3086598_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-15-baker/featured_huea3868b59f21d6e7f5f827a6c7bfc672_3086598_cf1ea99cd0d09a66adcb7739b6a37fc6.webp"
width="760"
height="544"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Image label" srcset="
/post/2022-11-15-baker/snipbit_huba30ffd477d23c69c36650b4ff3a03a6_59722_b3111a29dba5cb8fae838161a920b311.webp 400w,
/post/2022-11-15-baker/snipbit_huba30ffd477d23c69c36650b4ff3a03a6_59722_a61b176859dd8e82699f7d723ce9c508.webp 760w,
/post/2022-11-15-baker/snipbit_huba30ffd477d23c69c36650b4ff3a03a6_59722_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-15-baker/snipbit_huba30ffd477d23c69c36650b4ff3a03a6_59722_b3111a29dba5cb8fae838161a920b311.webp"
width="622"
height="192"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>