<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Annie Kryvorutsky | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title>
    <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/anniekryvorutsky/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/anniekryvorutsky/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Annie Kryvorutsky</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/anniekryvorutsky/avatar_hu133f7d18d81b88c4759471c743a81a92_154742_270x270_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Annie Kryvorutsky</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/authors/anniekryvorutsky/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Native vs. European Deaths</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For my project, I decided to stem off my group project concept of deaths in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; and focused solely on the comparison of Native Egyptian death reports versus European death reports throughout the newspaper.  I chose to investigate this topic because I thought it would be interesting to see the attitudes of the British towards the natives through death reports and compare those attitudes with those towards Europeans and other British people. I had a very minimal previous knowledge of tensions between the natives and the British, because of British colonialism in Egypt, but I wanted to learn more about it and see if these tensions were reflected in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. I also wanted to compare the number of deaths reported for natives and Europeans, in hopes of seeing if there was a drastic difference within the number of deaths of each, or to see if there was bias in reporting deaths of either group when compared with real statistics of deaths in Alexandria.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I only focused on comparing the layout of native deaths and British/English deaths. I did this by completing 3 queries:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div/div/div[(matches(.,’dea[d,th]’,’i’)) and (matches(.,’native’,’i’))]/head&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div/div/div[(matches(.,’dea[d,th]’,’i’)) and (matches(.,’british’,’i’))]/head&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;code&gt;//div/div/div[(matches(.,’dea[d,th]’,’i’)) and (matches(.,’english’,’i’))]/head&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first query allowed me to find the headings of all divs that had both “death” and “native” in them, while the second and third allowed me to do the same while searching for “British” and “english” alongside “death”. I included both “english” and “British” in order to get as many relevant results as possible by using different ways of describing one group of people. I tried doing this with native deaths as well by searching “Egyptian”, but the majority of results were irrelevant since the word “Egyptian” comes up countless times throughout the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For my search of native deaths, I got around 180 results, while for the search of English/British deaths I got 150 results. I was able to visualize the data into 3 different charts. For the first chart, I made 2 separate bar graphs that showed the count of native and English deaths per month, quarter, and year. For the native death reports, a drastic majority occurred within the summer months, while for the English death reports, the death rate was highest in both the summer and winter months.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-1_hu6f1598d14b623a173fc779ff6b4f8a6f_92307_171fc31f9f4b5f19b4df48c8ade9e0df.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-1_hu6f1598d14b623a173fc779ff6b4f8a6f_92307_962e0b13fc43f35f95bd3add2198eadd.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-1_hu6f1598d14b623a173fc779ff6b4f8a6f_92307_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-1_hu6f1598d14b623a173fc779ff6b4f8a6f_92307_171fc31f9f4b5f19b4df48c8ade9e0df.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;465&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-2_hua0c2a359ebcc8a91767c52149de6aacd_87293_1fe4425df58b4ca4f25ad4e20a1feab2.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-2_hua0c2a359ebcc8a91767c52149de6aacd_87293_ef146ddb6dc1edecb16029757002f5e9.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-2_hua0c2a359ebcc8a91767c52149de6aacd_87293_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-2_hua0c2a359ebcc8a91767c52149de6aacd_87293_1fe4425df58b4ca4f25ad4e20a1feab2.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;445&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The second visualization I made was a tree map that highlighted the most commonly used headlines when reporting native and British deaths. Both charts showed “The Plague” headline to make up for most of the death reports, however native deaths had more than double the amount of plague death reports than British deaths. Furthermore, when looking at the general descriptions of headlines, it was obvious to me that the native death headlines were often much more gruesome and tragic than the British death headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chapter 5 of &lt;a href=&#34;https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=mdp.39015070450344&amp;amp;view=1up&amp;amp;seq=145&amp;amp;q1=alexandria&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Third Pandemic of Plague in Egypt&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt; highlights how Alexandria was a particularly easy city to get infected by the plague, because of its “crowded population, of middle class and poor people, living under bad housing conditions.” The plague had a case mortality rate of around 50% during the early 1900’s and every year had multiple cases of plague appearance between 1899-1930. This source also depicts which quarters in Alexandria had the most cases of plague, with Labban, one of the most infected areas, being inhabited by poor Egyptians and poor and middle-class Greeks, Maltese, and Italians. The least infected cities – Ramleh, Attarin, and Gomrok – contain modern European establishments and house the upper-class Alexandrians. This gives insight into why the plague was such a huge factor of deaths in Alexandria and why natives experienced a much greater number of deaths from the plague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;3&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-3_hu1d616e94f0785adaec84ec8886c98426_78303_b07000170bd97f363a5294e40a2c480f.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-3_hu1d616e94f0785adaec84ec8886c98426_78303_b8e6683747651bf6d6b96556a4db0ee4.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-3_hu1d616e94f0785adaec84ec8886c98426_78303_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-3_hu1d616e94f0785adaec84ec8886c98426_78303_b07000170bd97f363a5294e40a2c480f.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;519&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;4&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-4_hu6ae9c11f2d91bd11c21a117adbbaadfe_122022_b7a0924f89d01b606eb5611b412da13d.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-4_hu6ae9c11f2d91bd11c21a117adbbaadfe_122022_df6d41ed0b075386597f377ad71789a1.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-4_hu6ae9c11f2d91bd11c21a117adbbaadfe_122022_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-4_hu6ae9c11f2d91bd11c21a117adbbaadfe_122022_b7a0924f89d01b606eb5611b412da13d.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;527&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final visualization that I made from this search was a chart to show the frequency of death reports per page. I found that the charts for both nationalities were very similar, in that they both dramatically peaked at Page 3. However, my search for English death reports generated a lot more results in pages 4-7 than my search for native deaths did. I found this curious, but it makes sense since in the 8-page issues of the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, the Army and Navy section often appears on page 4, which I would assume mostly consists of British soldiers. Additionally, the Local and General section along with the Native Press section would report on most native Egyptian deaths, which are both on page 3, and not many Egyptian deaths are reported outside that section.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;5&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-5_hua5c46045e6c1a3a3119e3afd97904d86_32019_f5a3dff42dc0c899644933bf1acd8ed5.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-5_hua5c46045e6c1a3a3119e3afd97904d86_32019_cb80a67862e000edebbfcb57bbca9ee3.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-5_hua5c46045e6c1a3a3119e3afd97904d86_32019_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-5_hua5c46045e6c1a3a3119e3afd97904d86_32019_f5a3dff42dc0c899644933bf1acd8ed5.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;421&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;6&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-6_hu221bc1c5534bfe7119f94290e64a25ad_33329_3ea3c38c6941cfa43d10be6eeee1d81b.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-6_hu221bc1c5534bfe7119f94290e64a25ad_33329_90a52902323a177539cdcdb7e5c6ec2b.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-6_hu221bc1c5534bfe7119f94290e64a25ad_33329_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-6_hu221bc1c5534bfe7119f94290e64a25ad_33329_3ea3c38c6941cfa43d10be6eeee1d81b.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;423&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Diving deeper into the language associated with deaths in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I decided to focus solely on the Local and General section, since I did not want any deaths outside of Egypt in my data set. Doing this, my estimate that there were more native deaths reported than European was once again reassured through seeing the results of my query. In order to find my results, I used the find and replace feature in Oxygen XML Editor, using regular expression to find &lt;code&gt;[A-Z][a-z]+ (?=[a-z, ]+dea[d,th])&lt;/code&gt;. I restricted this to the X-Path search: &lt;code&gt;//div[@feature=“local”]&lt;/code&gt;, and got around 1300 results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Looking closer at my results, I found that most dates that showed up in the results had around 5 results, all in the same sentence, which inflated the search result amount by a great amount. The reason this happened was because this search located multiple words before “death” but only one word showed up in each search result, causing a large inflation of results. I tried troubleshooting this issue but resorted to keeping all the data and just relying on proportion in my final visualization rather than distinct count. I wanted to do a similar search with finding the words after death in the Local and General section, but after completing the search, I found that these results weren’t useful to me since they mostly just described how the deaths occurred, not who they occurred to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Following the procedure of using regular expression to clean up my results, then pasting the results into Excel, I then used a word counter to show me the frequency of keywords before “death”. Pasting this data into Tableau, I was able to make a visualization showing the greatest frequency of these words and I deleted the results that were irrelevant to my query.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;7&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-7_hu5837968377d910b8291ad7821a188669_57998_0ab0eaf3651f5bc0dad67149215262a4.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-7_hu5837968377d910b8291ad7821a188669_57998_3965b14d24773b8cd3fb6e2299d3420a.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-7_hu5837968377d910b8291ad7821a188669_57998_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-kryvorutsky/annie-7_hu5837968377d910b8291ad7821a188669_57998_0ab0eaf3651f5bc0dad67149215262a4.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;561&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With native deaths making up around 1/5th of the death reports in my results, it became obvious that there was a sharp difference in the number of deaths reported on native Egyptians versus the number of deaths reported on Europeans. Surprisingly, “British” or “English” were nowhere near the top keywords; rather Greek was the next largest notable nationality, followed by Sudanese at around half the number of cases as the former. This could be explained by the fact that Alexandria was occupied mostly by Egyptians, with around 18% of the population being composed of Europeans. According to &lt;a href=&#34;http://www6.econ.hit-u.ac.jp/areastd/mediterranean/mw/pdf/18/18.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Cairo and Alexandria at the Beginning of the 20th Century&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, the highest percentage of foreigners in Alexandria were Greeks at around 30%, then Italians at 15%, and Syrians at 14%.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Egyptian Death Reports</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our group decided to focus on death reports throughout the Digital &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. Since this topic has already been thoroughly examined by other students in the past, we had to find something that would add new insight to how the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; reported upon deaths in the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s. As a result, we decided to study the various components of life in Egypt that affected death and its subsequent presence in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; as reports, articles, and expositions. We also researched how violent crime is reported in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; in comparison to murder. Throughout various research methods, we discovered that death was one of the most prevalent topics of conversation in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Death is something that is very often reported throughout the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, with multiple cases reported per day. Going through thousands of results for the words &amp;ldquo;death&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;dead&amp;rdquo; would be a hard task in order to find trends and useful insight to how the British in Alexandria spoke on death in the early 1900&amp;rsquo;s. However, we still started with a very broad query search to get a basic idea of the organization of death reports throughout the newspaper. We used X-Path to search for all the headings of &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt;s that contained the words “dead” and “death”, without paying attention to whether the words were uppercase or lowercase, by searching &lt;code&gt;//body/div/div[(matches(.,’dea[d,th]’,’i’))]/head&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gave us a search result of 3458 items, which we then used regular expression in Sublime Text to just keep the dates, headings, and page numbers of our results. After this, we organized the results into excel, proceeding to use Tableau to create visualizations of Death Headings throughout the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;. We were able to organize the data with a bar graph to show the frequency of death reports per month, quarter, and year. This gave us a basic idea of which seasons deaths occurred the most in, which could be significant in understanding life in Alexandria during the early 20th century.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From this visualization, we clearly saw that deaths most often occurred in peak winter and summer months, with January 1906 having the greatest number of occurrences of death. According to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.dropbox.com/sh/xa8w9338b7yoyow/AADjpeAbqmqfe3_5PYE4dpdja?dl=0&amp;amp;preview=Judicial-adviser-1904.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Judicial Adviser Report&lt;/a&gt; from 1904 written by the British Judicial Adviser, death was most frequently caused by vengeance and cupidity. These months often lead to an increase in social interaction, which therefore caused an increase in feelings of greed and retribution. As a result, death sharply increased.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;1&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-1_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_216177_c4f955f3532ff31d4215375bac07f286.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-1_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_216177_bf4a24c10f9a01692114299eead00f03.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-1_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_216177_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-1_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_216177_c4f955f3532ff31d4215375bac07f286.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;474&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another way we were able to visualize the data of all dead headings throughout the repository was by finding which headings death was most often reported under. We completed this by using a tree-map to show the most often used headings. Through this visualization, it was revealed that the “Local and General” heading was most often used by far; there were almost 300 results under this heading. The next largest headings were “Northern Italy,” “Personal and Social,” “Telegrams,” “Death,” “The Plague,” “Obituary,” and “Death”. This type of visualization was helpful in allowing us to identify the basic structure of where deaths are reported in the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;2&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-2_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_141405_3b3efdfb357ec5ffe8715abc2f9aa8db.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-2_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_141405_87d4904deeee0cfdef89e70d93178554.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-2_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_141405_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-2_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_141405_3b3efdfb357ec5ffe8715abc2f9aa8db.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;502&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We also investigated the features that most often featured the words “Death,” “Dead,” and “Died”. The X-Path query we used for this was &lt;code&gt;//div[matches(.,’death’,’i’)]/@feature&lt;/code&gt;, once again adding the “i” to ignore the case of the word, then changed the word inside the apostrophes to “dead” then “died”, going through every div to find the features that included these words. I did this in a slightly more tedious way that I could’ve done, but I got separate results for each word, which showed the frequency of the words in each feature. My results showed that the features “local,” “wire,” “social,” “birthDeathMarriage,” “obituary,” and “army” had the largest amount of death reports in them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;3&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-3_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_224235_54e6ddcfabe6c3013fe9fb6924abb6b8.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-3_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_224235_18221b2c7de2aecd6571a5f4fb7fa67f.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-3_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_224235_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-3_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_224235_54e6ddcfabe6c3013fe9fb6924abb6b8.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;587&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The final visualization we made to help us understand the headings of death was a comparison between the count of death headings and the page number that they occurred on. This visualization showed us that death occurred on every single page, but was much more frequently reported on Page 3, which had 1,167 reports of death; around 10 times more than any other page. This makes sense since the 3rd page most often reports telegrams, local and general, and personal and social sections. These were some of the sections that had the most frequent reports of death.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;4&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-4_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_65298_a3f9fc186f1c8ee8080fee71eb760b38.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-4_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_65298_9cfae7a6cb0e60fb07c68515b17a2086.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-4_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_65298_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-4_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_65298_a3f9fc186f1c8ee8080fee71eb760b38.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;422&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With all this information about the layout of death reports in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;, I wanted to find some additional insight to death reports that would help me understand more about the reports themselves, rather than just the layout of the reports. I figured that looking into the language used when describing these deaths would be very beneficial in broadening our understanding the way that the British in Egypt talked about death. In order to do this, I decided to use a simpler to find more words in the divs surrounding the word “death”. I did this by using the X-Path query &lt;code&gt;//div[@type=“section”]/div/p[contains(.,’death’)]&lt;/code&gt; to find the divs with the word “death” in them, which produced around 350 results, then followed the same procedure of using Sublime Text, and then using Excel to section the data into 2 columns of dates and words. However, instead of going straight to Tableau afterwards, I used the Online Word Counter linked in the resources tab of the Digital &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt; page. After pasting all my results in, excluding the dates of each report, the word counter generated a list of the most frequent words used in my data. I then created another Excel sheet with only this information and connected it to Tableau, creating a bar graph visualization of the most frequently used words around the descriptions of deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;5&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-5_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_125338_fc8623a4d1ca507c4556be7256709b90.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-5_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_125338_c166899f3d97f5b72b8354f89cc64bf5.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-5_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_125338_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-analysis-death-group/pic-5_huef301e84bbc013e28bd96e71336c2741_125338_fc8623a4d1ca507c4556be7256709b90.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;561&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Discarding the unimportant words, which mostly happened to be numbers such as “one” and “two”, along with some extra words that didn’t provide any insight into the language around death, I found that the visualization provided a good data set of words. Predictably, the top two most common words found were “death” and “deaths.” Nevertheless, looking further down the bar graph we found that the most frequent deaths involved topics such as hospitals, Alexandria, native, plague, Cairo, Egypt, fatal, treatment, and many other words. This proved to be incredibly insightful, as it not only allowed me to see the words used to describe death, but it also showed me which types of deaths were more frequent than others, or which the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt; prioritized.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For instance, hospital deaths were by far the most frequent, with a frequency of 116. This may ironically be because of the improvements to the healthcare system in Egypt during the 19th century, which would cause more people to rely on the hospitals. According to &lt;a href=&#34;https://dash.harvard.edu/bitstream/handle/1/10015270/Aksakal.pdf?sequence=1&amp;amp;isAllowed=y&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Asakal and Hutt&lt;/a&gt; the “medical schools, hospitals, pharmacies, sanitation systems, and inspection regimes” are similar to the public health institutions and systems that are used in modern times as well. While the developments were ahead of their time, they had the problem of constantly being short of resources. This prevented the reforms from being good as they could have been. This improvement in the medical systems could have increased the confidence the public had in the medical systems, which would have increased the number of people that went to hospitals. The lack of resources would have made their treatment more difficult, resulting in a large proportion of deaths in Egypt being hospital deaths.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also found that native deaths were very commonly reported, with a frequency of 107. This seems important since it could possibly show the contrasting conditions between native Egyptians lives and European lives in Alexandria. The plague was also a large factor of deaths reported, which most likely tie into the hospital deaths as well. The visualization revealed that the gender ratio of deaths was nearly the same; “woman” was used 29 times and “man” was used 28 times out of the death reports I gathered. This highlighted that there is not much bias or difference in frequency between the deaths of women versus deaths of men throughout the &lt;em&gt;Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Going down the graph, the frequency of words slowly decreases, yet a lot of descriptive words such as “European,” “Greek,” and “murder” were used around 20 times each. This once again gives a better understanding of which types of deaths most often occurred or were reported on. There was a small amount of children deaths, with a frequency of 15, and many more descriptive words that had a frequency of around 10. The list of words goes down to a frequency of 2, but I only captured the top of the bar graph to capture the most important or most frequent language that surrounded death reports in the &lt;em&gt;Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baltic Fleets Pass Through Suez Canal</title>
      <link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-24-kryvorutsky/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-24-kryvorutsky/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On Saturday, December 31, 1904, the Egyptian Gazette dedicated a section in the newspaper to announce the future arrival of the third division of the Baltic Fleet at Port Said.  It was implied that high precautionary measures were taken along the Canal when the second division passed through it, and it was noted that measures will still be taken, but they won’t be as extensive with the third division passing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;d-flex justify-content-center&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Image label&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /post/2022-10-24-kryvorutsky/featured_hu56e804dd2c3b6457cb4edd334f3144b6_97744_507a21ff7b750301fc61cf9ba2d741d0.webp 400w,
               /post/2022-10-24-kryvorutsky/featured_hu56e804dd2c3b6457cb4edd334f3144b6_97744_3c0af5987fc82668d3e00d0dc2f49243.webp 760w,
               /post/2022-10-24-kryvorutsky/featured_hu56e804dd2c3b6457cb4edd334f3144b6_97744_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-10-24-kryvorutsky/featured_hu56e804dd2c3b6457cb4edd334f3144b6_97744_507a21ff7b750301fc61cf9ba2d741d0.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;529&#34;
               height=&#34;527&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found it curious that the Egyptian Gazette found this information so much more important than the other information it notes about the Baltic Fleet, as this was one of the rare inclusions of the Baltic Fleet that was put into its own section rather than in the telegrams section.  However, looking deeper into it, I found that it makes sense that the newspaper prioritized this information, since there was clear wariness and hesitancy about Russia on Britain’s end.  Russia was seen as a great world power, and “&lt;a href=&#34;https://babel.hathitrust.org/cgi/pt?id=mdp.39015007658308&amp;amp;view=1up&amp;amp;seq=345&amp;amp;q1=Russia&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;aroused suspicion and fear in England.&lt;/a&gt;”  Russia was even cautioned to not make any attacks on the Canal earlier in 1877, which it slightly violated in 1904, during the time when the Baltic Fleets were passing through the Suez on the way to battle Japan.  Great Britain was even more wary during this time since Japan was their ally, and the nation was on risky terms with Russia already.  While getting coal to fuel the ships journey back to Russia, one vessel used the coal in “overhauling neutral ships near the entrance to the canal.”  This was a direct violation of the Convention of 1888, which forbade acts of hostility in the Suez Canal.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Furthermore, the Suez Canal played a large role for the Russians during the Russo-Japanese War time.  For one, it served as a &lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/16-analysis-stefonek/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;passage&lt;/a&gt; for the Russians to get to Japanese territory quicker and more efficiently, allowing them to rest and fuel up during their journey.  Moreover, it served as an easier means of providing reinforcement to vessels, such as when Admiral Rozhestvensky’s ship sunk near Madagascar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/books/edition/War_in_the_Far_East/C8sNAAAAIAAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=0&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.google.com/books/edition/War_in_the_Far_East/C8sNAAAAIAAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=0&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.google.com/books/edition/Japan_Weekly_Mail/SyZCAQAAMAAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=1&amp;amp;dq=baltic&amp;#43;fleet&amp;#43;suez&amp;#43;canal&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA655&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://www.google.com/books/edition/Japan_Weekly_Mail/SyZCAQAAMAAJ?hl=en&amp;amp;gbpv=1&amp;amp;dq=baltic+fleet+suez+canal&amp;amp;pg=RA1-PA655&amp;amp;printsec=frontcover&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-arenas/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/18-analysis-arenas/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
