<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Japan | Digital Egyptian Gazette</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/japan/</link><atom:link href="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/japan/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Japan</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/media/icon_hu3ccbb7e8d76090b34f602b231dc00fc8_804790_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Japan</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/tag/japan/</link></image><item><title>Russo-Japanese War</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-grove/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-grove/</guid><description>&lt;p>The image from my newspapers discusses advancements, rumors, and overall stories from the Russo-Japanese War, which took place from February 1904 to September 1905, and led to the first time a European power lost to a non-European Army, and established Japan as a military power leading to the increased militarization of Japanese society that had dwindled in years previous. The article discusses how Russian counterattacks were being repulsed, and that the Japanese were on the offensive and were succesfully taking over parts of Port Arthur. Eventually, the Japanese did take over Port Arthur, which allowed them to land more men into the mainland and take the fight to the Russians. At this point in time the Russians knew they needed help from through their alliances, so their agents throughout Europe, such as those in Hull, would try to make up reasons to get other countries involved in the war, such as bribing fisherman to say they saw torpedo-boats. This would most likely cause a country to join the war, which would help the Russians. Overall, the main tone of the sections is that the Japanese are overwhelmingly winning, and the Russians are on the backfoot. This could be caused because the British were closely allianced with Japan, and that is why the article does not mention the tremendous casualities the Japanese took to take Port Arthut when compared to the Russians.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img alt="Japanese mass casualty waves to take Port Arthur from the heavily defenced Russian forces" srcset="
/post/2022-11-01-grove/PortArthur_hu05b21811b29feed1d621a3a4fcc3b5cf_1973097_97857a10c3cca5491713a388233871b9.webp 400w,
/post/2022-11-01-grove/PortArthur_hu05b21811b29feed1d621a3a4fcc3b5cf_1973097_aead5d794f499c71a6722f0201c41698.webp 760w,
/post/2022-11-01-grove/PortArthur_hu05b21811b29feed1d621a3a4fcc3b5cf_1973097_1200x1200_fit_q75_h2_lanczos_3.webp 1200w"
src="https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2022-11-01-grove/PortArthur_hu05b21811b29feed1d621a3a4fcc3b5cf_1973097_97857a10c3cca5491713a388233871b9.webp"
width="760"
height="542"
loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Why is anarchy important in British Egypt?</title><link>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-11-ortiz-russian-anarchy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://dig-eg-gaz.github.io/post/2017-04-11-ortiz-russian-anarchy/</guid><description>&lt;p>According to the telegraphs, a man by the name of Matteo Moral, a known Anarchist, attempted to assassinate King Alfonso of Spain with a bomb. After being confronted by a police officer, Moral killed the officer. Shortly after, to evade capture, he committed suicide by shooting himself through the heart. Alongside Moral, an English tourist named Hamilton was also arrested under the charges of being an anarchist. The article does not state any more details about Hamilton&amp;rsquo;s arrest other than the Spanish authority refused to release him to the British.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="https://github.com/dig-eg-gaz/dig-eg-gaz.github.io/blob/master/images/Russian-Anarchy.png?raw=true" alt="Russian Anarchy" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It is interesting that the assassination attempt happened in Spain but it is being reported on by the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> in British Egypt. Why is anarchist activity important to the British? Before communism was the boogeyman of Europe, anarchism seemed to be the ideology that was branded the enemy of the state. A year prior to this assassination attempt, the Russian state was under threat of &amp;ldquo;anarchy&amp;rdquo; during the Russo-Japanese War. That was also reported by the &lt;em>Egyptian Gazette&lt;/em> in an article called &amp;ldquo;IS IT PEACE&amp;rdquo; which can be located in the June 1, 1906 edition on page two. Anarchism was an ideology that threatened the state was a whole. In an age where the state extended its power through colonial empires, anarchism threatened to dismantle the colonial system by weakening the state. To Great Britain, tracking anarchist activities of competing empires is important because it is a way to evaluate how strong the enemy central state is.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For more general information and history on anarchism as an ideology, feel free to read Noam Chomsky&amp;rsquo;s article, &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="http://inthesetimes.com/article/16081/a_history_of_anarchism/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">A Brief History of Anarchism&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>
&lt;figure >
&lt;div class="d-flex justify-content-center">
&lt;div class="w-100" >&lt;img src="Anarchist-Arrested.png" alt="Anarchist Arrested" loading="lazy" data-zoomable />&lt;/div>
&lt;/div>&lt;/figure>
&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>